Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
I love you.
我爱你。
Thank you.
谢谢。
All right, welcome back to the Ethereum Protocol Fellowship Study Group.
好的，欢迎回到以太坊协议研究小组。
Today, we have a special presentation from Mario on how to run a node.
今天，我们从Mario进行了有关如何运行节点的特别演讲。
go deep into what the the the hardware and and process of running a node and then we'll have
深入了解硬件和运行节点的过程，然后我们将拥有
lots of times for questions uh after he does a demo of how to get it set up and start running
在他进行演示如何设置并开始运行之后，很多次提出问题
a test net yeah thank you so much for the intro josh um yeah and welcome everyone to the node
测试网是的
running workshop. Yeah, there is a lot to interrupt here. It's it's finally the time to put things in practice it's it's been a lot of theoretical knowledge, a lot of talk about the protocol architecture or the concerns execution layer, etc, etc. But today, I want to show you how it actually works, how we put it into practice. So as I, if you remember my very
跑步研讨会。是的，这里有很多打扰。终于是时候将事情放在实践中了，这是很多理论知识，关于协议架构或关注执行层等的很多讨论等。但是，今天，我想向您展示它的实际工作方式，我们如何将其付诸实践。所以我，如果你还记得我
first presentation, I asked you, what is Ethereum? It's protocol, it's love, it's the future,
我问你，什么是以太坊？这是协议，是爱，这是未来，
and now we will become all of it, we will become Ethereum by actually running it, by actually
现在我们将成为所有事物，我们将通过实际运行它来成为以太坊
using it. So it's pretty exciting. Yeah, it's super pale, like the camera, anyway.
使用它。所以这很令人兴奋。是的，无论如何，它像相机一样超级苍白。
I am also watching the questions, feel free to drop questions in the Discord,
我还在观看问题，随时在不和谐中删除问题，
There's dedicated thread to that.
有专门的线程。
However, a part of that, you can follow the workshop.
但是，其中一部分可以跟随研讨会。
So what I will be doing is figuring it by myself,
所以我要做的就是一个人弄清楚它，
because I do this like maybe more than once a week,
因为我这样做大概每周不止一次
but it's still for you.
但这仍然适合您。
There's so many different clients and I remember all the flags and all the niches.
有很多不同的客户，我记得所有的旗帜和所有壁ni。
So, you know, I will be I will be going as it is a go to install and run it here.
因此，您知道，我将要去安装并在此处运行。
room and you can follow what I'm doing, you can try it yourself. If you run into any issues
房间，您可以跟随我的工作，您可以自己尝试。如果您遇到任何问题
that I'm not able to answer during the workshop, we will have time after that. After this is
我无法在研讨会期间回答，之后我们将有时间。之后
over, it would switch to Jitsi for more interactive session if you wish, if you guys want to share
结束，如果您愿意，它将切换到Jitsi进行更多的交互式会话，如果您想分享
your screen and troubleshoot, because here only I will be sharing my screen. I also brought,
您的屏幕和故障排除，因为这里只有我将共享我的屏幕。我也带来了
I was connected with my phone in case my microphone did this trouble, so we can test it later.
如果我的麦克风遇到了这种麻烦，我可以与手机联系在一起，以便我们以后可以对其进行测试。
First, I will share my screen.
首先，我将分享我的屏幕。
Yeah, awesome, awesome.
是的，很棒，很棒。
So what you are looking at is Debian 12 virtual machine.
因此，您正在查看的是Debian 12虚拟机。
So let's start with the basics, actually.
因此，实际上，让我们从基础知识开始。
Let's start with going to the workshop outline so I know what I'm supposed to talk about
让我们开始进入研讨会大纲，以便我知道我应该谈论什么
because I outlined it all here.
因为我在这里概述了这一切。
So yeah, let's start with the introduction.
是的，让我们从介绍开始。
So yeah, this is the doc with all the resources you will need.
是的，这是拥有您需要的所有资源的文档。
You can just click to get into all the places from here.
您只需单击即可进入这里的所有位置。
But let's start with the short recap of what we discussed before in the fellowship, I believe,
但是，让我们从简短的回顾开始，了解我们在研究金中讨论的内容，我相信
you in the study group, because I'm sure you folks understand what the node is, what the
您在研究小组中，因为我确定您的人们了解节点是什么，什么是
client is at this point.
客户在这一点上。
Just to recap, like, why you want to even do this, it's to use Ethereum, right?
只是回顾一下，就像为什么要这样做，这是使用以太坊，对吗？
So we are going to take the actual implemented spec and all of the behavior that Ethereum
因此，我们将采用实际实施的规范和以太坊的所有行为
is supposed to do, and we are going to execute it ourselves, which means there will be different
应该这样做，我们将自己执行它，这意味着会有不同的
stages, different operations that a client is doing, and of course it's a client pair,
阶段，客户正在做的不同操作，当然是客户对，
so there's execution and consensus client.
因此，有执行和共识客户端。
Now, why would you want to do this as an individual is to be able to actually use Ethereum.
现在，您为什么要作为一个人这样做是能够真正使用以太坊。
If you are using your wallet, if you are developing smart contracts, if you are anyway interacting with Ethereum, checking transactions on Blog Explorer, for example,
如果您使用的是钱包，如果您正在开发智能合约，则无论如何您都与以太坊进行互动，例如在博客资源管理器上检查交易
you're always using some third party provider, the wallet, RPC provider, etc.
您一直在使用一些第三方提供商，钱包，RPC提供商等。
You're trusting someone else's node about its view on the current state of Ethereum.
您信任别人对以太坊当前状态的看法的节点。
But this way, you can run your own client and, you know, just do it in a trustless way, because it's free, open software, so you see exactly what is being executed, what is being done, and you can verify chain on your own machine, basically.
但是，这样，您可以运行自己的客户端，您知道，只需以一种无信任的方式进行操作，因为它是免费的，开放的软件，因此您可以准确地看到正在执行的内容，正在执行什么，您可以在上面验证链条上的链条基本上是您自己的机器。
Now, first thing is to choose the client pair, to choose the actual combination of what node
现在，第一件事是选择客户对，选择什么节点的实际组合
we want, what client implementation we want in the weeks before you learn there is many
我们想要，在您得知有很多的几周内，我们想要什么客户实施
of them um a good overview is uh this one with all the different the different execution clients
他们中的一个很好的概述是与所有不同的执行客户端不同的概述
and consensus clients yeah and also tips on running them we might be using this later
共识客户是的，也是运行它们的提示，我们稍后可能会使用此信息
because it's full of great tips and explains basically the whole process and also some
因为它充满了很棒的技巧，并且基本上解释了整个过程，还有一些
simple minimal commands for each client so how to choose the client uh is to read some of their
每个客户端的简单最小命令，因此如何选择客户uh是阅读他们的一些
some of their um basic documentation here maybe but also it's up to you like whether you want to
他们的一些UM基本文档可能在这里，但这还取决于您是否想
invest your time in a specific language and specific code base for example you are
将您的时间投入特定的语言和特定的代码基础，例如您
a java developer so you might be more comfortable with best you because you understand its approach
Java开发人员，因此您可能会更适合您的最佳状态，因为您了解它的方法
more, et cetera. So the language is one thing. Another part is the client diversity. This is
更多，等等。因此，语言是一回事。另一部分是客户多样性。这是
more important if you are running the main node long-term or using running Validator, but
如果您要长期运行主节点或使用运行验证器，那么更重要的是
we won't really care about this, and we will actually default to get, which is the majority
我们不会真正关心这个
here. I decided to use it for a default get for two reasons. First, it's most used for a reason,
这里。我决定出于默认情况下使用它，原因有两个。首先，它是出于某种原因，
because it's easy to use, it works well, there won't be any surprises. And a part of this,
因为它易于使用，所以它运行良好，因此不会有任何惊喜。这是其中的一部分
like the easy configuration, it also has pretty good logs. It really explains well what it's
像简单的配置一样，它也具有非常好的日志。它确实很好地解释了它是什么
actually doing, and we can learn from it. And we can, of course, if we have extra time, we will
实际上，我们可以从中学习。当然，如果我们有额外的时间，我们将
swap it for another client. The combination doesn't have to be the same. It's the same thing
将其交换为另一个客户。组合不必相同。这是同一件事
implemented in different languages. That may cause troubles if you don't have a proper testing, but
用不同的语言实施。如果您没有适当的测试，那可能会引起麻烦，但是
as the week four explained us, we have pretty robust testing which ensures all the different
正如第四周解释的那样，我们进行了非常强大的测试，可确保所有不同
clients should talk to each other. And does it work on ARM? Of course it runs ARM. The different
客户应该互相交谈。它可以在手臂上工作吗？当然，它可以运行手臂。不同的
clients provide binaries for different architectures, but also you can compile it yourself on an
客户为不同架构提供二进制文件，但您也可以自己编译
ARM machine or even REST.
手臂机甚至休息。
But, yeah, so, yeah, first thing, choosing the client pair.
但是，是的，是的，第一件事，选择客户对。
So I would advise you folks, you can completely go with the get and lighthouse that I will,
所以我建议你们，你可以完全选择我会的灯塔和灯塔，
but you can just choose any other client.
但是您只能选择任何其他客户。
I would do a little challenge.
我会做一些挑战。
Like, I'm not sure how many people are here in the stream right now.
就像，我不确定现在有多少人在这里。
But, you know, if we have at least, like, 20 people,
但是，您知道，如果我们至少有20个人，
we should be able to run, like, every client combination maybe.
我们应该能够像每个客户组合一样运行。
So it would be pretty cool if you want to try different combos.
因此，如果您想尝试不同的连击，那将很酷。
Like, feel free to write down in the chat, like,
就像，随时在聊天中写下，就像
what combination are you going to try.
您要尝试什么组合。
And when you choose a client, you go ahead to its documentation.
当您选择客户时，您将继续使用其文档。
documentation so learning about here I had some examples uh here with uh best where you go on
文档，所以在这里学习我有一些示例
right so we can you can read about to open the get a lighthouse documentation in our case uh this
是的，所以我们可以阅读要打开灯塔文档，以便在我们的情况下
goes to releases we go to dogs here and I before you know running the main node before investing
发行发行，我们在这里去狗，我在您知道在投资之前运行主要节点
hardware and so on, I will recommend studying the docs.
硬件等等，我建议研究文档。
In case of Lighthouse, they have this Lighthouse book.
如果灯塔，他们有这本灯塔书。
Let's see how easy it is to find the docs from their GitHub.
让我们看看从他们的github找到文档有多容易。
Is it this one?
这是吗？
No, it's not docs.
不，不是文档。
These are not docs.
这些不是文档。
It's the Lighthouse book.
这是灯塔书。
I wonder where it's the link.
我想知道它在哪里。
Here it is, Lighthouse book.
在这里，灯塔书。
Yeah.
是的。
So, we opened the docs, and we will follow this.
因此，我们打开了文档，我们将遵循这一点。
And yeah, so we choose the clients,
是的，所以我们选择客户，
we make ourselves familiar with what is going to happen.
我们使自己熟悉将要发生的事情。
And yeah, we have best-seller tech for JavaScript tablets,
是的，我们有用于JavaScript平板电脑的畅销书，
awesome, red lighthouse for mainnet, it's pretty cool.
很棒的红色灯塔，用于主网，非常酷。
Okay, we have three combinations already.
好的，我们已经有三个组合了。
And yeah, and the environment,
是的，环境，
this is another important thing.
这是另一回事。
So many people were asking about
这么多人问
hardware requirements and so on.
硬件要求等。
For this workshop, I want to keep the hardware requirements
对于这个研讨会，我想保留硬件要求
as minimal as possible.
尽可能最小。
What you are looking at right now is a KVM, a virtual machine.
您现在正在查看的是KVM，这是一台虚拟机。
I don't even have an HTOC.
我什至没有HTOC。
I just did it today for the purpose of this workshop
我今天只是为了这个研讨会
to demonstrate how to do it on a fresh system.
演示如何在新鲜系统上进行操作。
So we have, like, yeah, three CPU cores.
因此，我们有三个CPU内核。
I've allocated six exi-memories.
我分配了六个Eximories。
It will be a very, very small instance.
这将是一个非常非常小的实例。
And if you, I mean, of course, this is also doing some graphical interface, minimal graphical
当然，我的意思是，这也是在做一些图形接口，最少的图形界面
interface, but you can do this on a virtual server.
接口，但是您可以在虚拟服务器上执行此操作。
You can just rent a small VPS for like four bucks a month, and that's enough to run a
您可以每月租用一个小型副总裁大约四美元，这足以运行
family node, for example, or just try it yourself.
例如，家庭节点，或者自己尝试。
So regarding the environment, we are using WLinux here.
因此，关于环境，我们在这里使用Wlinux。
It works on any Linux distro.
它可以在任何Linux发行版上使用。
It works in Windows.
它在Windows中起作用。
It works in Mac OS.
它在Mac OS中起作用。
Mac will be similar to what I'm doing here.
Mac将与我在这里所做的类似。
the windows steps might be more much more different but again you go to the docs and we
Windows步骤可能会更加不同，但是您又转到文档，我们
start with introduction installing get and um uh here you see the first goes mac os even before
从介绍安装get and um uh开始，您甚至在此之前都看到第一个go Mac OS
linux here is uh ubuntu windows so you follow the you follow the instruction specific to your
Linux是UH Ubuntu Windows
system here um i will be demonstrating those for uh for debian based distros so yeah i think
系统嗯，我将为Debian基于Debian的发行版展示它们，所以是的
we can get into it by obtaining clients um uh how to for installation yeah so this so yeah this is
我们可以通过获取客户um UH如何安装来了解它，是的，是的，这是
a fresh install but i already installed some basic things yeah you see i was missing h top but yeah
一个全新的安装，但我已经安装了一些基本的东西，是的，您看到我缺少H顶部，但是是的
So in Debian, you can use your package manager, ideally.
因此，在Debian中，您可以理想地使用软件包管理器。
For some compilers which might be outdated in your package manager, especially in Debian,
对于某些包装经理，尤其是在Debian中可能已经过时的编译器，
I have a bunch of outdated packages in Debian, you want to go straight to the website and
我在Debian有一堆过时的包裹，您想直接访问网站，
download it, go lang, you can download it binary, there's REST and so on.
下载它，去Lang，您可以下载二进制文件，休息等。
didn't install docker either uh but uh yeah so let's see if i ins have the gpg i think i have
不是安装docker嗯，但是是的，所以让我看看我是否有GPG，我想我有
yeah it's already installed okay cool uh because we will need that just in this in a second
是的，它已经安装了好的酷呃，因为我们只需要在一秒钟内就需要
Maybe, yeah, Josh, can you make it, like, you know, make it make it full screen so it
也许，是的，乔什，你能做到吗
will do a piece of screen there.
将在那里做一块屏幕。
But, yeah, and let me know if the mic is okay.
但是，是的，让我知道麦克风是否还可以。
Let me know if you can hear me well, because there is a lot of typing and so on, so I can
让我知道您是否能听到我的声音，因为有很多打字等，所以我可以
I guess we should phone Mike in case it's bothering you too much.
我想我们应该给迈克打电话，以防万一它困扰您太多。
Yeah it just won't disappear.
是的，它不会消失。
Did I lose the mic?
我失去了麦克风吗？
I was just trying to remove the little square there.
我只是想拆除那里的小广场。
It's okay.
没关系。
No, it's perfect.
不，这是完美的。
Awesome.
惊人的。
I just wanted to have a bit more space in the stream.
我只是想在流中有更多的空间。
Let's go into it.
让我们进入它。
So let's obtain.
因此，让我们获得。
Yeah, if it gets too much, let me know.
是的，如果得到太多，请告诉我。
I will try the different things.
我将尝试不同的事情。
But let's start with the obtaining clients.
但是，让我们从获得的客户开始。
So the most basic way how to obtain a client is to download its compiled binary.
因此，获得客户的最基本方法是下载其编译的二进制文件。
So this is like already finished piece of software you can just run, right?
因此，这就像您可以运行的已经完成的软件，对吗？
We can download it and execute it.
我们可以下载并执行它。
So these executables are in download pages.
因此，这些可执行文件在下载页面中。
you saw the one for Lighthouse in the releases.
您在发行版中看到了灯塔的那一家。
Let's hit Installation, and then for the get, we saw it here, right?
让我们点击安装，然后为了获得，我们在这里看到了，对吗？
So let's go with get, and yeah, we choose the platform, right?
因此，让我们继续吧，是的，我们选择平台，对吗？
And we obtain the binary.
我们获得了二进制。
But what I'm doing here is I'm downloading already finished piece of software from already
但是我在这里做的是我已经下载已经完成的软件已经
from, that I'm basically have to trust, right?
我基本上必须信任，对吗？
This is something that was compiled by someone else.
这是其他人汇编的东西。
I cannot, you know, look into it, make sure that it's, that it's according to the code
我知道，我不能研究它，请确保它是根据代码
because it didn't compile it myself.
因为它自己没有编译。
We can demonstrate the compilation later, but I don't want to waste time on it right
我们稍后可以演示汇编，但我不想浪费时间
now.
现在。
What we can do is to verify the signature of the binary.
我们可以做的是验证二进制的签名。
So get signs, you can also check some here,
因此，获得标志，您也可以在这里检查一些
get signs, their binaries with PGP,
获得迹象，他们与PGP的二进制物，
with keys which are listed in the bottom here.
在此处列出的键。
See, we can import them here or download them directly.
看，我们可以在这里导入它们或直接下载它们。
In our case, we want this Linux builder key.
在我们的情况下，我们想要这个Linux构建器密钥。
Yeah, okay, we have it here.
是的，好吧，我们在这里。
So now let's import the key,
所以现在让我们导入钥匙，
and let's import a key,
让我们导入钥匙，
and yeah, yeah, I'm finally getting it.
是的，是的，我终于得到了。
I got it released recently,
我最近发布了它，
and I hope it will still work.
我希望它仍然有效。
Yeah, it will keep it, it's pretty simple.
是的，它会保留它，非常简单。
gpgimport, so now we are doing the public key cryptography
GPGimport，所以现在我们正在进行公共密钥密码学
that all the Ethereum is based on, right?
所有以太坊都是基于的，对吗？
Oh wait, this is my quest builder.
哦，等等，这是我的任务建造者。
Did it click on the Linux one or the MacOS one?
它是否单击Linux One或MacOS One？
Yeah, this is the Linux builder.
是的，这是Linux建造者。
So now I use my local GNU PGP key chain
所以现在我使用当地的GNU PGP钥匙链
p keychain to import a public key of this go ethereum linux builder which is a key that
P键链导入此GO Ethereum Linux Builder的公共密钥，这是一个关键
signs the linux binaries and it's part of my keychain.
标志着Linux二进制文件，这是我的钥匙扣的一部分。
I can now use it to verify this signature here.
现在，我可以在此处使用它来验证此签名。
So we have this one.
所以我们有这个。
This is the signature, which is, let's go bigger for the quotes.
这是签名，这是让我们更大的报价。
Yeah, this is the signature which is verifiable against the public key.
是的，这是可以根据公钥进行验证的签名。
So let's do that simply by gpg verify, and now we can actually just pass the pubkey,
因此，让我们简单地通过GPG验证来做到这一点，现在我们实际上可以通过Pubkey，
it will find the it will find uh uh the signature and then it will find the binary so you see we
它会发现它会找到签名，然后找到二进制文件，以便您看到我们
have a good signature from this builder so um so we can be we can be sure um yeah added it
从这个建筑商那里有一个很好的签名
added to my keyring with uh with this import yeah so now we can be a bit more sure that the nobody
是的
nobody tempered with our binary because so especially if you are uh you know running some
没有人对我们的二进制纠正，因为尤其是如果你是嗯
serious architecture uh some serious infrastructure uh if you're running a validator this is
严重的体系结构UH一些严重的基础架构，如果您正在运行验证器，这是
necessary to do this is something that ensures the integrity of the file because maybe this
这样做必要的是确保文件完整性的事情，因为也许
downloads get dot ethereum org maybe it compromise maybe there is a hacker serving malicious binaries
下载获取以太坊org dot org，也许会妥协，也许有一个黑客服务恶意的二进制文件
trying to you know spy on you steal from you destroy theory and whatnot so you want to you
试图让您知道间谍您从窃取您的理论和什么，所以您想向您致意
want to make sure you you do this or you compile it yourself um to compile maybe i can do it
想确保您执行此操作或自己编译，嗯，也许我可以做到这一点
quickly uh maybe i can do it very quickly while we it hosts um but yeah i want to demonstrate it
嗯，也许我可以在我们主持的时候很快做到这一点，但是是的，我想证明它
if you are not aware of this it's very it's important step uh if we do something like this
如果您不知道这一点，那是非常重要的一步，如果我们这样做
starting with yeah and to actually to yeah we can just make cat if we have yeah there are different
从Yeah开始，实际上是的，如果有不同的话，我们可以做猫
this one interesting thing i can show you if you're if we are um compiling get you can actually
如果您正在编译，我可以向您展示这一件有趣的事情，实际上可以
get bunch of different utilities. So here we want to just clone the repo. And then I
获取一堆不同的公用事业。因此，在这里，我们只想克隆回购。然后我
would avoid compiling lighthouses when thinking about it, because, like, Rust compilation
在考虑时会避免汇编灯塔，因为像生锈
times are terrible, so maybe it might be faster. And I hope my internet doesn't degrade too
时代很糟糕，所以也许可能更快。我希望我的互联网也不会降低
it's downloading um anyway um here in lighthouse let's head to the pre-built binaries as well
无论如何，它在灯塔中都下载了UM，我们也要前往预先建造的二进制文件
and here we have information on um different releases so let's go to the releases page and
在这里，我们有有关UM发行版的信息，所以让我们转到“版本”页面，然后
look into it uh we don't want experimental three states release this is a version of
研究它，我们不希望实验三个状态发布这是一个版本
lighthouse which changes are the database architecture to three states and it's just
更改的灯塔是到三个州的数据库体系结构，这只是
experiment right now we want the this is the latest um stable release five one oh uh we see the
实验现在我们希望这是最新的UM稳定版本五个OH，我们看到了
uh changes the change log here um and oh it's actually it's actually important hotfix so
uh在这里更改更改日志嗯，哦，实际上它实际上很重要，所以
what we want to see is here so here we have um uh here uh we have uh the binaries for uh for
我们想看到的是在这里
the lighthouse so let's download it um let's it's still it takes a while anyway so let's also
灯塔所以让我们下载吧
actually uh one thing so if you are using a vps you know if you are using if you just have a some
实际上一件事，所以如果您使用VPS，您知道是否正在使用，如果您只有一些
remote branded server or if you don't have gui uh you don't need to just click on this but we can
远程品牌服务器或如果您没有GUI UH，您不需要单击此功能，但是我们可以
you can just get a link and download it download ourselves like this um yeah now it's downloading
您可以获取链接并下载它，就像这样下载自己，现在正在下载
lighthouse but i'm going to kill it because it's actually i don't like to so i was using vget w get
灯塔，但我要杀死它，因为它实际上我不喜欢
there but what you can do is use curl for that and you can enforce tls v 1.3 so to make sure that
在那里，但是您可以做的就是将卷曲用于此操作，您可以执行TLS v 1.3，以确保
it's actually end-to-end encrypted with the server you are downloading it from so if you want to be
它实际上是通过您要从下载的服务器进行加密的端到端加密的，因此，如果您想成为
fancy you can download it binaries like this yeah and we have it right here
喜欢您可以像这样下载它的二进制文件，我们就在这里
it holds yeah nothing downloads anyway let's actually unpack it now so we
无论如何，它都没有任何下载任何内容，让我们现在实际上打开包装，所以我们
have both binaries now it's still still cloning the repo anyway it's a huge repo
现在有两个二进制文件
Let's un-tar it. You guys know that tar is from the tape archiver, so it's literally, like, from the tapes.
让我们吧。你们知道焦油是来自磁带档案架的，所以从字面上看，焦油是从磁带上来的。
Okay, yeah, and we have the .lighthouse here, amazing. Let's get rid of this, and let's bring the .org.
好的，是的，我们在这里有.Lighthouse，很棒。让我们摆脱这一点，让我们带上.org。
Yeah, we have the cat binary here, and this.
是的，我们在这里有猫二进制。
And now we are here in home with both our binaries with lighthouse and cat, right?
现在，我们和灯塔和猫一起都在这里与我们一起在家里，对吗？
So this is unpacked.
因此，这是打开包装的。
it's like, oh, I didn't check the lighthouse before I didn't check the BGP key.
就像，哦，我没有在没有检查BGP密钥之前检查灯塔。
I'm not sure if I should do that, but maybe let's show you, because, yeah, you guys, I
我不确定我是否应该这样做，但也许让我们告诉你，因为，是的，你们，我
see that you guys were, yeah, it depends.
看到你们是的，这取决于。
There are some key servers which might give you troubles.
有一些关键服务器可能会给您带来麻烦。
Download it again.
再次下载。
And it's funny it's cloning so slow, but downloading, yeah.
它很有趣，它的克隆很慢，但是下载，是的。
Let's use it.
让我们使用它。
This is the key.
这是关键。
To obtain the key, you need to get it from a key server.
要获取密钥，您需要从密钥服务器中获取它。
Maybe they also have it somewhere, but it's probably somewhere in a key server.
也许他们也可以在某个地方使用它，但是它可能在密钥服务器中。
So we go to the GPG, key server, keys, openPGP.org, maybe.
因此，也许我们转到GPG，密钥服务器，密钥，OpenPGP.org。
Search keys, and we pass the key.
搜索键，我们通过钥匙。
Yeah, Sigma Prime.
是的，Sigma Prime。
Yeah, yeah, awesome.
是的，很棒。
Let's do it.
我们开始做吧。
it. And now you want to invert it. Yeah, okay, yes, we have it imported. We can list our
它。现在您想倒转。是的，好的，是的，我们将其导入。我们可以列出我们的
keys to show you guys we have all of them. So we have the Mac builder that we accidentally
向大家展示我们所有人的关键。因此，我们有Mac Builder，我们不小心
did, the Linux one that we used for get, and now we have the Sigma Prime. So now we can
做到了我们用于Get的Linux One，现在我们拥有Sigma Prime。所以现在我们可以
actually get the signature that i didn't verify before oh did it do portable or or
实际获取我在哦之前没有验证的签名，它做了便携式或或
yes portable yeah so the difference here and you can maybe notice it in other software
是的，便携式是是的，所以这里的区别，您可以在其他软件中注意到它
in other clients the difference here is that um this is compiled uh with different uh rest
在其他客户中，这里的区别在于，嗯，这是与不同的uh rest一起编译的
compiler um uh targets different different configuration and there are some systems some
编译器UM UH目标不同的配置，并且有些系统有些
architectures like some maybe debian virtual machine which won't understand certain instructions
诸如某些debian虚拟机之类的体系结构，这些机器无法理解某些说明
compiled with the with the default most performance mode so this is like uh of course if
使用默认的性能模式编译，因此，这当然就像UH
you want to achieve the best performance which means like gain maybe smaller like few percent
您想取得最好的表现，这意味着收获可能较小，例如百分之几
of the of the performance it's best to compile your client in your own machine
在性能中，最好在自己的机器中编译您的客户
hello to gentle users um yeah so we have the oh i don't have it it downloads anyway um
向温柔的用户问好，是的，所以我们有哦，我没有它下载嗯
and now we can gpg verify this one
现在我们可以gpg验证这个
and we have a good signature from Sigma Prime, security at Sigma Prime, that's nice. Okay,
我们在Sigma Prime的Security Sigma Prime有一个很好的签名，这很好。好的，
so I believe that if the key server is not compromised and the github is not compromised,
因此，我相信，如果密钥服务器不妥协并且github不妥协，请
we have a good plant right here. So actually let me remove all of this.
我们在这里有一个很好的植物。因此，实际上让我删除所有这些。
Now we have the get and lighthouse, it's really nice. And we are ready to launch it, basically.
现在我们有了获得和灯塔，这真的很好。基本上，我们准备启动它。
Here is the repo done, so we can go it here.
这是完成的存储库，所以我们可以在这里去。
In case you want to compile it, all it takes is to make it.
如果您想编译它，那么要做的就是制作它。
I don't have it make it.
我没有它。
Anything's still up on this first.
首先，一切都在此。
So you want to go to, yeah, always your documentation.
因此，您想始终转到您的文档。
There's some docs on compile here.
这里有一些文档。
3dst, okay, go from source, yeah.
3dst，好的，是的，是的，是的。
Doesn't mention all the dependencies.
没有提及所有依赖关系。
Yeah, I don't have to make mine anyway.
是的，无论如何我都不必做我的。
I believe I have go.
我相信我已经走了。
Yeah, it's working.
是的，它在起作用。
This is how it's still getting a bunch of other packages.
这就是它仍在获得其他包裹的方式。
But I just wanted to show you that, like, when I say make get, it's going to compile
但是我只是想向你展示，就像当我说《赚钱》时，它将编译
get, it's a utility get, which is one of the things that this repository can do.
得到，这是一个实用程序，这是该存储库可以做的事情之一。
It's like one binary which interacts with a bunch of other packages.
就像一个二进制文件与其他一堆软件包相互作用。
Here you can see the different packages.
在这里，您可以看到不同的软件包。
So, for example, we can have, like, boot node to run dev peer-to-peer communicator for consensus.
因此，例如，我们可以使用启动节点来运行Dev peer-per-Peer Communicator以达成共识。
So to just give you an example that I can do, like, not just make CAD, but I can, I
因此，给您一个可以做的例子，不仅是制作CAD，而且我可以，我可以
mean, I can make all, as the documentation suggests, if you want to do all the utilities.
意思是，如果您想做所有的公用事业，我可以像文档所建议的那样赚钱。
But let's just do it here.
但是，让我们在这里做。
So let's go here.
所以让我们去这里。
Here.
这里。
No.
不。
Okay.
好的。
Now.
现在。
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
Okay, now, so yeah, you can go build each of the parts of GAT.
好吧，现在，是的，您可以构建GAT的每个部分。
So if you want to, for example, experiment just with the peer-to-peer stack, you go to
因此，如果您只想尝试使用点对点堆栈，那么您可以去
this part and you compile this, or you can just make this is what the crawler was based
这部分是您编译的，或者您可以做到这一点，这是爬网的所基于的
on, for example.
例如。
So if you want to play with crawling nodes, you can just modify and compile this utility
因此，如果您想使用爬行节点，则可以修改并编译此实用程序
and so on.
等等。
So compiling the client gives you multiple benefits.
因此，汇编客户会给您带来多种利益。
First of all, you can just have those parts that you really want to use, exactly the same
首先，您只能拥有您真正想使用的那些部分，完全相同
compilation, configuration that you want, with the optimizations.
汇编，您想要的配置以及优化。
So it might be running a bit faster on your software and on your hardware, but most importantly,
因此，它可能在您的软件和硬件上运行得更快，但最重要的是，
I read the code, right?
我读了代码，对吗？
Here I can see exactly what is happening.
在这里，我可以确切地看到正在发生的事情。
can see uh that i'm running the actual code that i read and i compiled it by myself so yeah again if
可以看到我正在运行我阅读的实际代码，然后我自己编译了它，所以再次
you trust the compiler uh we have like a trustless setup here uh where we can run ethereum without
您相信我们拥有的编译器嗯，我们喜欢在这里不信任的设置
uh anybody interfering as a free software so yeah that's that's that's uh what i wanted to explain
呃，任何人都会干扰免费软件，所以是的，那就是我想解释的
with the compilation part but uh for developers for people who want to look into this go ahead
汇编部分，但对于想要调查这一点的人的开发人员来说，继续
but let's assume we have already compiled or downloaded it or whatever binaries now. We have
但是，假设我们已经对其进行了编译或下载或现在的任何二进制文件。我们有
row binaries here. So, of course, this is a technical workshop. I'm not using any
行二进制。因此，当然，这是一个技术研讨会。我不使用任何
third party to run this. There are these dev notes, Docker setups, and so on.
第三方运行这个。有这些开发笔记，码头设置等。
And I would say that for practical purposes, if you are actually going to run your node
我会说出于实际目的，如果您实际上要运行节点
long-term it might be even better to use something like some of these because it comes with all the
长期使用类似的东西可能会更好，因为它伴随着所有
packages pre-configured etc but if you want to learn how it actually works you need to look into
包装预先配置等，但是如果您想了解其实际工作方式，则需要查看
the configuration by yourself so that's what we are going to do now we are going to look how you
独自配置，这就是我们现在要做的，我们将如何看待您
actually configure it manually which again might cause some issues some troubles it might be
实际对其进行配置，这再次可能引起某些问题
it might be problematic for someone and it doesn't come like automatic from some
对于某人而言，这可能是有问题的，并且不会像某些人一样自动
packager like this, but it gives you the full control and insight and of course your technical
像这样的包装器，但它为您提供了完整的控制和洞察力，当然也可以
folks, so we will look into that.
伙计们，所以我们将调查。
So yeah, we've downloaded and verified the binary, we've compiled the clients, now let's
是的，我们已经下载并验证了二进制文件，我们已经编译了客户，现在让我们
run it on a test net.
在测试网上运行它。
So let's do it, let's run get.
因此，让我们开始吧。
Check it, I'm running get.
检查它，我正在跑步。
Okay, it was easy.
好吧，这很容易。
So yeah, basically just executing the binary here.
是的，基本上只是在这里执行二进制文件。
Minimize it Firefox.
最小化firefox。
Whether it's better.
是否更好。
There are any questions?
有什么问题吗？
Here's my little Discord thingy.
这是我的小不和谐。
No, wait, I have it.
不，等等，我有。
Okay.
好的。
it's just running Teco as a beacon node only
它只是仅作为信标节点运行teco
it's a validator it is I'm not sure exactly where did you read that in the documentation
这是一个验证器，我不确定您在文档中读到了什么地方
what it what does it mean but like uh we will get in there that like these uh consensus clients they
这是什么意思
come either integrated with extra package of um of um uh the validator client so there is the
与um um uh uh uh uh uh uh uh uh um uh um uh um uh
node itself which is connected to other beacon nodes it's making it work in the validators we're
连接到其他信标节点的节点本身，它使其在验证器中起作用
doing all these validator duties uh but now we are we start with execution part we start with get
做所有这些验证者职责呃，但是现在我们是从执行部分开始的，我们从get开始
because like just like two years ago or less this would be all you need to run it through it fully
因为就像两年前或以下的时间一样
so let's read the log so let's let's before we configure it let's actually look at a default
因此，让我们阅读日志
configuration so we can execute it it runs the default configuration which is of course ethereum
配置以便我们可以执行它运行默认配置，这当然是以太坊
mainnet with some default values so we will first look into this and then how to how to configure
具有一些默认值的主网，因此我们将首先研究一下，然后如何配置如何配置
how to change it um so yeah starting starting uh get on main net as default here is uh the cache
如何更改它um，是的，是的，启动uh在主网上默认是uh uh
that it uses for for main net um here is the peer count so it's targeting targeting maximum of 50
它用于主要净UM的是同行计数，因此目标最多针对50
peers uh garbage collection gas cap 50 million uh so this yeah um uh this is this is setting the
同行UH垃圾收集气帽5,000万UH，所以是的，嗯，这就是设置
the gas per node uh yeah there are different kzg libraries you can choose so it is using
每个节点的气体呃，是的，您可以选择不同的kzg库
the go implementation of kzg which is needed for the quad for uh what what is the different yes
Quad需要的KZG实现是什么是什么不同的是
I'm sorry, I have to break it here, but there's a question about the different kinds of data availability.
对不起，我必须在这里将其打破，但是关于不同类型的数据可用性有一个问题。
I think I missed the question before. So to answer you, there is basically two kinds of things.
我想我以前错过了问题。因此，要回答您，基本上有两种事情。
One is like full node, which can be achieved over snapsync or full sync, and there is archive node,
一个就像完整的节点，可以通过snapsync或完整同步实现，并且有存档节点，
which is full sync, but the difference is that a full node doesn't keep all the
这是完全同步的，但区别在于，一个完整的节点并不能保留所有的节点
historical states so if you want to the state is the current moment in ethereum where this user has
历史状态，因此，如果您想进入状态，则是以太坊的当前时刻
x amount of funds this contract has this values in this database and so on so the current snapshot
x资金数量该合同在此数据库中具有此值，依此类推，因此当前快照
of the all the values in ethereum is kept only for the last or um last x amount of maybe 100
以太坊中的所有值仅保留在最后一个或um的最后x量可能100
blocks or something in case of a reorg but it prunes all historical states because it's
如果是重复的块或其他东西，但它会修剪所有历史状态，因为它是
completely unnecessary so the archival node keeps all these all these historical states which is
完全不必要
only for certain purposes it's kind of useless and it's it's big amount of data so in in the
仅出于某些目的，这是无用的，它是大量数据，因此
default setup as here it is by default get the snapsync full node so you can see that
默认设置为这里，默认情况下是获取snapsync full节点，以便您可以看到
it's ancient, so all the historical data, all the blockchain data, which is not the
这很古老，所以所有历史数据，所有区块链数据，不是
current state, but the blockchain, which we verify all the hashes to the current value
当前状态，但是区块链，我们验证了当前值的所有哈希
to make sure it's a chain of blocks, that's kept in the ancient database, which is like
为了确保它是一系列块，它保存在古代数据库中，就像
this few hundred gigabytes of all the historical data.
所有历史数据中的几百千兆字节。
So this is, yeah.
所以，是的。
We can write into it, it's not doing it only.
我们可以写入其中，不仅仅是这样。
This is one small interesting thing it's using Pebble, instead of leveldb, it's not maintained
这是使用卵石而不是LevelDB的一件小小的有趣的事情
right now, so get switched to Pebble, maybe you can configure this as well.
现在，因此切换到卵石，也许您也可以配置它。
Initializing the Ethereum protocol, writing default main Genesis block, this is important.
初始化以太坊协议，编写默认的主要创世纪块，这很重要。
So you see, we ran get on mainnet by default.
因此，您会看到，默认情况下，我们跑了Mainnet。
So it uses it's in the get binary it has hard coded values of the Genesis block.
因此，它使用它在GET二进制中，它具有创世纪块的硬编码值。
The Genesis block itself is written in the client.
创世纪块本身写在客户中。
So it automatically knows what to start with.
因此，它会自动知道该开始的内容。
And it uses this hard coded defaulted main Genesis block to initialize the database.
它使用此硬编码的默认主体创世纪块来初始化数据库。
And here you see it's values.
在这里，您会看到它的价值。
So these are the configuration values coming from the Genesis that it's chain ID one main
因此，这些是来自Genesis的配置值，即它的链ID一个主
net, right?
网，对吗？
This was added for like, this is, this is like every, every Ethereum network has a different
这是为了添加的，这就是每个人，每个以太坊网络都有不同的
chain ID.
连锁ID。
So there are, you know, L2s, there are test nets, especially with higher values and every
因此，您知道有L2，有测试网，尤其是具有更高的值，每个值
fork of Ethereum, one of the millions you can see on CoinGecko has like some different
以太坊的叉子，您可以在Coingecko上看到的数百万
chain ID.
连锁ID。
This is important because with chain ID it's part of what you are signing with a transaction,
这很重要，因为有了链条ID，这是您通过交易签名的一部分，
which means it can't be replayed on another chain.
这意味着它不能在另一个链上重播。
It's an important protection which happens.
这是发生的重要保护。
So we see the current consensus is the proof of stake, depending on the beacon chain, merge
因此，我们看到当前的共识是股份证明，具体取决于信标链，合并
from it has work.
从中有工作。
And here are the premarriage, the original hard forks, and their height.
这是预后，原始的硬叉及其高度。
So you see when the Homestead DAO fork, all these pushes of fork bomb happen, Byzantium,
因此，您会看到当霍姆斯特德·道叉时
Berlin, you see the block heights.
柏林，您会看到街区高度。
So the client knows that at this block height, this sort of rules apply, right?
因此，客户知道，在此块高度下，这种规则适用，对吗？
And then there is the moment of the merge.
然后是合并的时刻。
Network is known to be merged.
已知网络合并。
it's already known in case like you know you're some older version of client you might still be
如果您知道自己是较旧的客户端，它已经知道了，您可能仍然是
able to sync it but it will figure out that it's merged later uh and this is the the the
能够同步它，但它会发现它以后合并了，这是
difficulty of the network at which point the network uh merges and post merge so yeah you see
网络的难度在此时网络合并并发布合并，所以您知道
all the all the fork data here um yeah the most recent block is number zero of course because we
嗯，最新块当然是零，因为我们
didn't it didn't have anything in the database um and then it's uh yeah it doesn't have any
它没有数据库中没有任何东西，然后是呃，是的，没有任何
snapshot it's trying to build the first snapshot and as you see it enabled snapsync so by default
快照它正在尝试构建第一个快照，并且如您所见，默认情况下它启用了Snapsync
it's running on snapscene the snapsync works in a way that it it downloads a snapshot from
它在Snapscene上运行，SnapSync以一种从中下载快照的方式运行
the network of like relatively recent state so like you know uh some finalized blocks before
相对较新的状态的网络，所以就像您知道之前的一些最终块
day old or something, and then it starts building from this moment.
Day Over或其他东西，然后从这一刻开始构建。
If we change it to it's still then it downloads all the historical data, right, and verifies
如果我们将其更改为它，那么它将下载所有历史数据，正确并验证
everything.
一切。
But it's more practical and much faster way how to do it.
但这是更实用的方法，方法更快。
It's a snapshot.
这是一个快照。
It's a different representation of the database.
这是数据库的不同表示。
So, like, the get database, the state database, the pebble or leveldb, it's the Merkle-Patricia-3
因此，就像GET数据库，状态数据库，卵石或LevelDB一样，它是Merkle-Patricia-3
Pebble thing, level DB thing, which is very different to the snapshot, which is like basically
鹅卵石的东西，水平的DB东西，它与快照截然不同，这基本上就像
just a database of the accounts and values, not a tree.
只是帐户和价值的数据库，而不是树。
So it needs to generate a snapshot.
因此，它需要生成快照。
Clients in the network generate these snapshots.
网络中的客户生成这些快照。
The other clients don't fetch it and then build based on them.
其他客户不会获取它，然后基于他们构建。
it you we see that it needs the beacon client to sync over the engine api uh yeah this is our
您看到它需要信标客户端在引擎API上同步，是的，这是我们的
our uh peer-to-peer uh it's there yeah here is our our uh as it connects to the computer network
我们的点对点UH在那里是我们的UH，因为它连接到计算机网络
it gives us uh the uh public key the identity of this node um it generates some default yeah nice
它为我们提供了uh uh upent键，该节点的身份um um会生成一些默认值是的
the ipc is communication endpoint very fast uh gwt is the authentication we will need for the beacon
IPC是通信端点非常快的uh gwt是我们需要的身份验证
we'll set it all up it also runs uh this another endpoint yeah this is it runs uh this http server
我们将全部设置为它也可以运行另一个端点，是的，这是它运行的uh uh uh此http Server
is for connecting you see it has enabled authentication because it's connecting to
用于连接您看到它已启用身份验证，因为它正在连接到
uh the beacon node or this is where and then when i killed it when i when i send the interrupt ctrl c
嗯，信标节点或这是我在发送中断ctrl c时杀死它的地方，然后杀死它。
it's it's writing down and shutting down all the endpoints.
它是写下并关闭所有终点。
So yeah, this is this is like a simple run of get.
是的，这就是一个简单的get。
I want to show you what happens when it starts.
我想向您展示它开始时会发生什么。
So before we configure it, before we before we run into into something more.
因此，在我们遇到更多东西之前，在我们进行配置之前。
Yeah, so let's let's make it screen.
是的，让我们让它屏幕吧。
I don't have screen help like that.
我没有这样的屏幕帮助。
that okay we don't need string uh let's just start let's just start okay so so uh now based
好的，我们不需要字符串嗯
on this you saw the default values you see how it behaves and now we want to um we want to um
在此上，您看到了您看到的默认值，现在我们想um um um
uh configure it ourselves make sure it behaves uh our our the way we want as you can see there is
uh自己配置它，请确保它以我们想要的方式行事
uh there was the default the default um uh that is the data store is dot perium in your home folder
嗯，默认的默认um uh是数据存储在您的主文件夹中的dot perium
which is not ideal for me i want to have it in some more obvious way and i want to run different
这对我来说并不理想，我想以一种更明显的方式拥有它，我想跑步不同
networks so we are going to make also a different uh get data let's also make lighthouse data um
网络，所以我们还将制作一个不同的uh获取数据，让我们制作灯塔数据UM
uh let me let me see uh questions quickly combination so if you're on a full node and
嗯，让我让我快速查看问题的组合，所以如果您在完整的节点上，
i want to grab all for sd or something what happens so you can see all the current data
我想抓住全部SD或其他事情，以便您可以看到所有当前数据
you can see how much your uh your account or sd or or any other token uh what they have in
您可以看到您的帐户或SD或任何其他代币的UH有多少
database right now but if you want to know it at a block 1 million four eight seven three somewhere
目前数据库，但是如果您想在一个街区100万四个八七分之一的街区中知道它
sitting you know five years ago uh you need to calculate it from the blockchain data you have
坐着你知道五年前，您需要从拥有的区块链数据中计算出来
and it's a lot of calculations so you need to archive these states for that so so so unless
而且这是很多计算
you want to you know calculate all the states based on the state transitions from from every
您想知道根据每个州的状态过渡来计算所有状态
transactions that you have in the blockchain data you just cache the created state you just keep it
您在区块链数据中拥有的交易您只需加速您只需保留创建的状态即可
and that's like kind of naive approach actually it's it's it's uh more complex in the red and and
这就像一种天真的方法实际上是在红色和
uh ergon they have this different database where they keep like the state changes and and it's
嗯，他们有这个不同的数据库，在该数据库中，他们像状态一样更改，并且是
much more complex it's like two three terabytes now and and you can have you have that but you
复杂得多，就像现在有两个三个trabytes，您可以拥有，但是您
don't really need it like nobody really is i'm running it because i like it no normal users
真的不需要它，就像没有人真正在运行它，因为我不喜欢普通用户
need this to interact with the network or to like you know fully verify the chain
需要它与网络互动或喜欢您知道完全验证链条
right but full node doesn't have all the full node has all the blocks has all this
正确，但完整节点没有所有完整节点具有所有块具有所有这些
ancient ancient data uh so when i go to we already opened uh yeah chain data
古老的古代数据嗯，所以当我去时，我们已经打开了uh是的链数据
here here we have uh all the all the all the data it's of course in this level db
在这里，我们在此级别db中都拥有了所有所有数据
pebble format which we cannot just read but it's all in here so you don't really uh you have you
鹅卵石格式我们不能只阅读，但这一切都在这里，所以你真的没有你有你
have all um you can check it exactly in the client documentation i don't want to lie but like
所有嗯，您可以在我不想撒谎但喜欢的客户文档中准确检查它
transaction receipts, the transaction info, the blocks, since it's still now it's part of
交易收据，交易信息，块，因为现在仍然是
full node. The big, like for example, what you're talking about is basically for force. In the last
完整节点。例如，大型，例如，您所说的基本上是为了武力。在最后
talk from Dom, he mentioned it as a part of pro to the history expiry, the EIP-444 talks about like
来自Dom的谈话，他将其作为历史到期的专业人士的一部分，EIP-444谈论
just you know not requiring this ancient or this like historical data to be uh to be uh
只是您知道不需要这个古老或像历史数据一样成为嗯
part of notes which would make it easier to run uh because you don't really need it you need a
笔记的一部分将使运行uh更容易，因为您真的不需要它
current state but yes to verify everything you keep all this data same genesis but in
当前状态，但可以验证所有您将所有数据保留相同的创世纪，但在
archive node you have these extra calculated states like that's the difference you want to
存档节点您拥有这些额外计算的状态，例如您想要的差异
yeah it emphasizes the difference between the archive and um and uh if you want to
是的，它强调了档案和UM和UH之间的区别
So, from a full node, you can be fully offline, you can have a full node, and you generate
因此，从一个完整的节点中，您可以完全离线，可以拥有一个完整的节点，然后生成
the archive node data from it, right?
档案节点数据，对吗？
You have all the data you need, you just need to do all the ridiculous calculation, which
您拥有所需的所有数据，只需要完成所有荒谬的计算，
is just too much to do it every time you want to do a query for some historical data, so
每当您想查询某些历史数据时，都无法做到这一点，所以
then you cache everything and you have an archive node.
然后，您可以缓存所有内容，并且有一个存档节点。
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
Okay, let's get back to this.
好吧，让我们回到这个。
it's the first thing I want to configure. We have the getdata, so let's use that. So
这是我要配置的第一件事。我们有GetData，所以让我们使用它。所以
first thing is it's data deer getdata. So first, we point get to store its data in this
首先是它的数据鹿GetData。因此，首先，我们指出要在此存储数据
directory. So if you are, for example, running the bigger node, if you need, like, you know,
目录。因此，例如，如果您运行较大的节点，则如果需要，请知道，您知道，
terabyte of storage, you probably might have, like, external SSD, might have, like, some
储存的Terabyte，您可能有外部SSD，可能有一些
external drive where you want to do this, so then it would point get to something like that, like
您想做的地方的外部驱动器，这样就可以指出这样的东西
media, whatever. But in our case, we just want a local, a different local
媒体，无论如何。但是在我们的情况下，我们只想要一个本地，不同的本地
database we can differentiate between networks, et cetera.
数据库我们可以区分网络等。
um okay uh then we can so yeah the sync mode the default uh is the snap that is the default we can
嗯，嗯
change it to full if we want um if you want to start from from the genesis but let's keep it a
如果您想从创世纪开始，请将其更改为Full
snap uh basically even if it's default this is not a minimal configuration by the way i'm showing you
基本上，即使是默认的，这也不是我向您展示的方式的最小配置
some more options that come into my mind but if you want to see like the minimum viable get config
我想到的还有更多选项，但是如果您想看到最低可行
you want to come here, write a node here.
您想来这里，在这里写一个节点。
So what do we need to do?
那么我们需要做什么？
Yeah, I didn't specify it, but the network is main net.
是的，我没有指定它，但是网络是主要网络。
Actually, I should have shown you help first.
实际上，我应该先向您展示帮助。
Yeah, let's show the help.
是的，让我们展示帮助。
So here you see all the options.
因此，在这里您可以看到所有选项。
It's kind of overwhelming.
有点压倒性。
I don't want to go through all of it,
我不想经历所有这些，
just because it's kind of, you know, you can read.
仅仅因为它是一种您知道的，您就可以阅读了。
So yeah, one important thing, there are commands.
是的，重要的是，有命令。
So I just executed get as the get node, but these are all the different commands, all the different utilities that you saw for using get via console, manipulating database, et cetera, et cetera.
因此，我只是作为获取节点执行了，但是这些都是不同的命令，您看到的所有使用GET GET CONSOLE，MANIPULATION DATABASE等cetera等的不同实用程序。
So, yeah, here you can see that.
所以，是的，在这里您可以看到。
This is for if you have an account within Get, you can use this.
这是为了如果您内部有一个帐户，则可以使用此内容。
These are some old ones, API.
这些是一些旧的，API。
So, yeah, we want to set up the authenticated endpoint,
所以，是的，我们想设置已验证的端点，
and we also want to set up the normal HTTP, which is false,
我们还想设置正常的HTTP，这是错误的，
which is closed by default.
默认情况下关闭。
So, we want to be able to talk to our nodes over the classic JSON RPC, which is this one.
因此，我们希望能够通过经典的JSON RPC与我们的节点进行交谈，这就是这。
And yeah, the default is it.
是的，默认值是这样。
We can maybe leave it at that.
我们也许可以把它留在那里。
Yeah, more, and also you can enable web sockets for different kinds of communications.
是的，更多，您也可以为各种通信启用Web插座。
Yeah, here is the, yeah, you can have all this config in one file, of course.
是的，这是，是的，当然，您可以将所有这些配置放在一个文件中。
You can point to that.
您可以指出。
is the pebble or level db option that i explained data the year and you can have you can split the
是我在一年中解释数据的卵石或级别DB选项，您可以将您分开
agents the the the historical data to see different uh different directories so for example you have
代理人的历史数据要查看不同的UH不同目录，因此您有
like a slower bigger disk with this and faster with uh with the later data oh and we and this
就像一个较大的磁盘一样，使用以后的数据哦，我们和我们和这个
is how we choose the network so we just pass it the network name these are the pre-configured
是我们选择网络的方式，因此我们只通过它将网络名称传递给这些是预先配置的
networks right mainnet holoshki and sefolia somewhere here yes sefolia um however uh get
网络正确的Mainnet Holoshki和Sefolia在这里是Sefolia um的地方
or any of these clients they can consume they can run on any compatible network but you just need to
或他们可以在任何兼容网络上运行的这些客户中的任何一个，但您只需要
supply the genesis and the nodes to connect to and it's able to run on another test net or someone
提供创世纪和连接的节点，并且能够在另一个测试网上运行或某人
it will demonstrate it soon.
它将很快证明它。
Um, yeah, security concerns when enabling HTTP API, this is a great question, and we
嗯，是的，在启用HTTP API时，安全问题是一个很好的问题，我们
will look into it, and let's look at the options.
将研究它，让我们看一下选项。
So yeah, so first of all, like, you are able to talk to your node.
是的，首先，您可以与您的节点交谈。
You use different namespaces based on that.
您使用基于此的不同命名空间。
can see it in the documentation here interacting with get so you see these are different namespaces
可以在此处的文档中看到它，以便您看到这些是不同的名称空间
which uh get enables and the most one the one that like kind of comes as potential dangerous is admin
uh得到启用，最多是喜欢的人，因为潜在的危险是管理员
because this one actually lets you like you know manipulate your node like add peers remove peers
因为这实际上让您喜欢您知道操纵节点（例如添加对等式）删除对等的节点
first thing i see here um so so um this one manipulates the node itself but also debug can
我在这里看到的第一件事嗯，所以这个操纵节点本身，但调试可以
be dangerous because there was a question here about like um uh the archival notes but for
要危险，因为这里有一个问题，就像嗯，档案笔记，但
example if you run like a debug ask about some some big piece of data from from historical moment
例如，如果您像调试一样跑步，请询问历史时刻的一些大数据
you can you can like deduce the node you can you can really like halt it because it's going
您可以喜欢推论节点，您可以真正喜欢停止它，因为它正在进行
to try to calculate it so uh there are different namespaces but by default you see it's exposed
尝试计算它，以便有不同的名称空间，但默认情况下，您会发现它已暴露
only in the local host so if you trust your local machine or your local network this should be all
仅在本地主机中，因此，如果您信任本地计算机或本地网络，则应该全部
right uh you can you know handle with firewall and so on but what you can also do is to decide
对，嗯，您可以知道使用防火墙等等，但是您还可以做的就是决定
which namespaces you want to use and i'm trying to find the um trying to find a comment here uh
您想使用哪些名称空间，我正在尝试在这里找到UM，以便在这里找到评论
which lets you out rp secret ql http address yeah api this one i'm i'm blind yeah so http.api
这使您可以让RP Secret Ql http地址是的，是的，我是我盲的，所以http.api
lets you choose only which of these namespaces you want to run so for example you only want to
让您仅选择要运行的这些名称空间中的哪个
run it to only give you the basic information about the ethereum chain so you can you can you
运行它只为您提供有关以太坊链的基本信息，以便您可以
just choose that you can you can do it as well um so this this can add like a bit bit
只需选择您可以做的，嗯，这可以添加一点
security as well so yeah thanks for the question um so yeah and it's most like it can be a ddos
安全也是的，是的，感谢您的问题，是的，最喜欢它可以是DDOS
problem so yes make sure you know you run it on a machine that you don't have ddos it's locally
问题所以是的，请确保您知道您在没有DDOS的机器上运行它
safe and so on yeah yeah if you want to run archive mode this is where you and i enable
安全等等，是的，如果您想运行存档模式，这就是您和我启用的地方
it you need to basically uh disable the garbage collection and uh uh you can you can run uh you
您需要基本上禁用垃圾收藏，呃，您可以运行呃
can just retain all the history but there are more it's just a story but for example cache
可以保留所有历史，但还有更多只是一个故事，例如缓存
pray images as well you see you can you can like cache bunch of things which is deleted by default
祈祷图像也可以看到您可以喜欢默认情况下删除的一堆东西
and mostly the node doesn't need it because it's trying to be as lightweight as possible
大部分节点不需要它，因为它试图尽可能轻巧
But okay, to run it with some reasonable values.
但是好的，用一些合理的值运行它。
So we've already started on that here.
因此，我们已经在这里开始了。
So let's continue.
所以让我们继续。
We want to run and this time let's run on Holoshki.
我们想跑步，这次让我们在holoshki上跑步。
So let's add it to the front.
因此，让我们将其添加到前面。
Holoshki.
Holoshki。
and uh yeah from we want to enable the http so let's enable that we can choose the port or the
嗯，是的，我们想启用HTTP，所以让我们启用我们可以选择端口或
address uh yeah the default is 85545 i'm just demonstrating uh and there are various other
地址嗯，默认值为85545，我只是在演示uh，还有其他各种
things like again like for the security purposes what you can do is i could have showed it here
再次出于安全目的，您可以做的是我可以在这里展示它
it's better than typing it.
比键入更好。
I'm sorry, I'm a bit all over the place.
对不起，我到处都是。
So yeah, you want to choose what hosts are authenticated
是的，您想选择已验证的主机
to connect to you, which host name is authenticated
要连接到您，哪个主机名已验证
to talk to the RPC.
与RPC交谈。
So this is something that can also add a bit of security,
因此，这也可以增加一些安全性，
but also can give you trouble if you're remote
但是，如果您遥不可及，也会给您带来麻烦
accessing your own node and you have troubles.
访问自己的节点，您会遇到麻烦。
Yeah, you can use this wildcard, but it'd be safer with that.
是的，您可以使用这个通配符，但这会更安全。
yeah so that's it's another thing we want to do uh so this is like the json rpc but now there is the
是的，所以这是我们想做的另一件事，所以这就像JSON RPC，但是现在有
rpc which actually um uh which you actually need to be able to talk to the consensus client which
RPC实际上您实际需要能够与共识客户端交谈的RPC
is the JWT authenticated endpoint, and it's out RPC, it's enabled.
是JWT身份验证的端点，并且已启用了RPC。
So this one is going to let us point it to a place where the value should be.
因此，这将使我们将其指向值应该是值的地方。
So let me explain this.
所以让我解释一下。
So to communicate between the execution and client, which is crucial, it's basically
因此，要在执行和客户端之间进行交流，这是至关重要的，它基本上是
like within the software it's like one piece of Ethereum talking to another, right?
就像在软件中一样，就像以太坊在与另一个以太坊交谈，对吗？
It's like, you know, if you split get to two binaries or something, they need to have a
就像，您知道，如果您分开到两个二进制文件之类的东西，他们需要有一个
safe way to communicate.
安全的交流方式。
And we do it with this Java web token.
我们使用此Java网络令牌来做到这一点。
It's basically just a random 32-bit hex, just a big number, which they need to both client
这基本上只是一个随机的32位十六进制，只是一个很大的数字，他们都需要这两个客户
both clients need to know them to be able to talk. So, we create it either with the open
两个客户都需要了解他们才能交谈。因此，我们在开放的情况下创建它
manually, but we don't need to do that. We just tell him that let's put it to slash temp,
手动，但我们不需要这样做。我们只是告诉他，让我们削减温度，
slash JWT. Yeah. And yeah, I think that's basically it. This is really the basic things
Slash JWT。是的。是的，我认为基本上就是这样。这确实是基本的事情
you want to configure. If you're running the node, you want to know where your data is,
您要配置。如果您运行节点，您想知道数据在哪里，
you want to know where your HTTP communication is running, and this sort of default, the elder PC,
您想知道您的HTTP通信在哪里运行，这种默认的Elder PC，
the port, the default is 8551. I'm going to keep it like that just to demonstrate.
端口，默认值为8551。我要保留它只是为了演示。
So, yeah, this should be it. Let's see if it complains. No, it's running. So now you see
所以，是的，应该这样。让我们看看它是否抱怨。不，它正在运行。所以现在你看到了
that it's running on 1700, which is the postcode of Prague 7, Holešovice, and it's all of these
它是在1700上运行的，即布拉格7的邮政编码，holešovice，这就是所有这些
hard forks and the merge happen at the moment zero in the genesis, right? So it's already done.
硬叉和合并在创世纪的零时发生，对吗？所以已经完成了。
it's done.
完成了。
And then the Shanghai happens that Cancun activates at one point.
然后，上海发生了坎昆在某一时刻激活的。
Okay, it's already found two peers, and it's running.
好的，它已经找到了两个同行，并且正在运行。
But as you can see it's the post-merge network, so the consensus is beacon, but there is no
但是，如您所见，这是合并后网络，因此共识是信标
beacon client seen, so we need to launch one.
可以看到信标客户端，因此我们需要启动一个。
That's our next challenge.
那是我们的下一个挑战。
Let's keep the window with get in here, and let's grab it under terminal, and let's move
让我们随身携带窗口，然后在终端下抓住它，然后移动
to lighthouse.
到灯塔。
So, yeah, again, we have the lighthouse documentation here.
所以，是的，再次，我们在这里有灯塔文档。
We can get the client, and we see, yeah, so we get a JWTC grid.
我们可以找到客户，是的，所以我们得到了JWTC网格。
It was created in the temp.
它是在温度下创建的。
Yeah, it's here.
是的，在这里。
uh you can read it right uh this is the value the very secret value please don't compromise my note
嗯，您可以正确阅读它，这是一个非常秘密的价值的价值
but yeah it's just communicating within the vm in the localhost so it should be okay
但是，是的
so we have that we have the execution node and now we want to well we don't want to do staking
所以我们有我们有执行节点，现在我们想好我们不想做
but we want to run the node so yeah here or the very similar example should be should be somewhere
但是我们想运行节点，所以在这里是的，否则应该在某个地方
clear. Yeah. I think, like, there are these basic examples on Ethereum.org, but I did this,
清除。是的。我认为，就像以ethereum.org上有这些基本示例，但我这样做了
I wrote this around the merge. And since then, you know, maybe some flights are duplicated or
我围绕合并写了这篇文章。从那以后，您知道，也许有些航班重复或
renamed or something. So, like, better follow the documentation. And here you can see it's also
重命名或其他。因此，最好遵循文档。在这里，您也可以看到它也是
asking us for a checkpoint sync. We will do it, but it will do it in a moment. Let's start with
要求我们同步检查点。我们会这样做，但它会稍后做。让我们开始
it's just the default. So let's run lighthouse, we have it here, you can see it's also many
只是默认值。因此，让我们运行灯塔，我们在这里有，您也可以看到它也有很多
options it gives us, and they are mostly pretty similar to get, but also very different in
它为我们提供的选择，它们大多与GET相似，但也有很大不同
the beacon part, but the basic configuration is similar. We need to choose a network, a
信标部分，但基本配置相似。我们需要选择一个网络，一个
data dir, and connect it to the API, so let's do that. So we want to lighthouse, so there
数据DIR并将其连接到API，所以让我们这样做。所以我们想灯塔，所以
are these different commands you see uh account manager beacon node uh validator client so
您是否看到这些不同的命令，您会看到UH客户经理Beacon Node UH验证器客户端，所以
basically vn is the beacon node bc is the valid client these are two different features two
基本上VN是信标节点BC是有效的客户端，这是两个不同的功能两个
different behaviors two different modes or basically pieces of like code path within this
不同的行为在此内两种不同的模式或基本上类似的代码路径
lighthouse binary which lets us to either run the beacon node uh or run a validator client which
Lighthouse二进制
connects to a beacon node so if we are going to stake this is something we need to do later but
连接到信标节点，因此，如果我们要赌注，这是我们以后需要做的事情
first we need to set up the the beacon node so it starts with that we want network polish key
首先，我们需要设置信标节点，以便从我们需要网络抛光密钥开始
the execution end point uh is yeah actually the one that it says here yeah we can pretty much
执行终点uh是的，实际上是在这里说的是，是的，我们几乎可以
pretty much yeah yeah uh i the the one thing to be to be careful with if like some clients do
是的，是的，嗯，如果像某些客户一样
some don't like require the protocol here uh what happens to me i just forget like okay lighthouse
有些人不喜欢这里的协议，吗
wants the http part there right and like in get you don't need it for example so um that's
想要正确的http部分
something that i always start working so yeah and the execution jwt token was in stamp jwt
我总是开始工作的东西，是的，执行JWT令牌是在邮票中
Okay, and we also enable the HTTP endpoint.
好的，我们还启用了HTTP端点。
And we are basically ready.
我们基本上已经准备好了。
So now we are running Lighthouse.
所以现在我们正在运行灯塔。
So what is happening now, this is a funny thing that I wanted to show you.
因此，现在正在发生的事情，这是我想向您展示的一件有趣的事情。
Because as I showed you before, it has the hard-coded Genesis file and it writes it down
因为正如我之前展示的那样，它具有硬编码的创世纪文件，并将其写下来
and everything.
一切。
case of Holeški and Lighthouse it's a kind of kind of funny thing because Holeški network
Holeški和Lighthouse的情况是一种有趣的事情，因为Holeški网络
uh launched with like a huge uh uh a huge amount of validators and if you have all of these funded
UH发行了大量的验证器，如果您拥有所有这些资助的人
validators this big uh this big value uh it's a lot of space to take it's a lot of like it's a
验证者这个很大的价值，这是很大的空间，就像它是一个一样
million and a half validators so it's like whatever at least million and a half um records
百万半验证者，这就像至少有百万半的记录
of this it's like a huge amount of data so the the deposit uh sorry uh with uh the the genesis
这就像大量数据，所以存款对不起，呃，嗯
um in case of in case of um beacon node it's like the configuration values in some json format
um，如果有UM信标节点，则像某些JSON格式的配置值一样
and the actual state in ssd format it's so big it's like 100 something megabytes so they decided
和SSD格式的实际状态是如此之大，就像100个兆字节，所以他们决定
that instead of putting another 100 megabyte file as a part of their binary they are just going to
而不是将另一个100兆字节的文件作为其二进制文件的一部分
hard code um this aws address where you get the uh yeah so this may take time on testings with
硬码UM这个AWS地址您可以在哪里获得uh是的，所以这可能需要时间进行测试
large wallet accounts this is meant for holish key so on mainnet this shouldn't happen if i go
大钱包帐户这是为了为整体钥匙而
network main app he's not going to tell me uh starting from known genesis okay here he is
网络主应用程序他不会从已知的创世纪开始告诉我，他是
downloading the Genesis state.
下载创世纪状态。
And then we fail.
然后我们失败了。
Syncing from Genesis insecure and capital with data availability checks.
从创世纪不安全和资本同步数据可用性检查。
You should install it from a checkpoint sync.
您应该从检查点同步安装它。
Oh, really?
哦真的吗？
That's interesting.
那很有意思。
Why is it insecure Genesis sync?
为什么它是不安全的创世纪同步的？
So I understand why it's insecure to download a Genesis from this random
所以我明白为什么从这个随机下载创世纪是不安全的
server right here but i'm surprised it does the same on main net and it forces me to checkpoints
服务器就在这里，但令我惊讶的是，它在主网上也可以做同样的事情，并且迫使我进入检查点
because in checkpoints sync you then trust um you don't trust um the checkpoints providers but let
因为在检查点同步您，您就会相信您不信任检查点提供商，但让我们
me show you so what we can do on uh with the post merge network with the beacon uh with the
我向您展示，所以我们可以通过与信标UH一起在UH上做些什么
beacon notes finalizing is that uh you know if there is some block finalized like some
信标笔记最终确定是，您知道是否有一些块最终确定
time ago, like hours or days ago, it's probably not going to be it's not probably going to be just
时间前，就像几个小时前或几天前一样，可能不会只是不仅仅是
what's it word, re-worked so easily. I don't assume that like you know the history like
这是什么话，很容易重新工作。我不认为就像你知道的历史
few days ago will change because it would require like a major slushing incident of billions and
几天前会发生变化，因为它需要像数十亿美元的重大泥泞事件一样
billions of dollars, so I consider this finalized moment in the history of the chain as
数十亿美元，所以我认为这条连锁历史上的最终时刻是
it's like as safe as or maybe even safer as Genesis because I don't want to trust some
就像我不想信任一些人一样安全，甚至更安全，甚至更安全
random Genesis I'm downloading it from the server but instead we trust these endpoints so there are
随机创世纪我正在从服务器下载它，但是我们信任这些端点，所以有
um different providers as you can see and what we do is that um we connect to their notes here this
如您所见，不同的提供商以及我们要做的是，我们在这里连接到他们的笔记
using beautiful Checkpoint software and you see what what um Epoch is finalized and therefore
使用美丽的检查点软件，您可以看到什么UM时期最终确定，因此
uh we can it has it's known you can you can check this data the state through the block route uh
嗯，我们可以知道您可以通过块路由检查该数据
with other nodes to make sure it's safe you know and it's serving this Checkpoint here this 20
使用其他节点，以确保您知道它是安全的，并且在这里为此检查点提供了20个检查站
it all finalized, finalized, um, uh, block as our kind of Genesis that like we, uh, that
所有这些都最终确定，最终确定，嗯，嗯，封锁是我们的创世纪，就像我们一样，呃，
we, we start from here.
我们，我们从这里开始。
So yeah, so it's kind of subjective, like, uh, so we, we call it, we call it weak subjectivity
是的，所以这是一种主观的，例如，嗯，我们称之为我们称之为虚弱的主观性
checkpoints and, uh, it should be covered in the week three.
检查站，嗯，应该在第三周介绍。
You can look into that.
您可以研究一下。
You can look more into the weak subjectivity.
您可以更多地研究弱主观性。
There is a good part on this somewhere here.
这里有很大的一部分。
So it says it's proof-of-stake with subjectivity.
因此，它说这是主观性证明。
You can read about this here.
您可以在这里阅读有关此信息。
So this is about the subjectivity checkpoints.
因此，这是关于主观性检查点的。
So we are going to use this website, and thanks to it's take care, we are going to download
因此，我们将使用此网站，并且由于它的注意，我们将下载
We're going to download there.
我们要下载那里。
Let's just randomly choose one.
让我们随机选择一个。
If you do this on mainnet, you should check it between different nodes and different operators
如果在主网上执行此操作，则应在不同的节点和不同的操作员之间进行检查
to have more security.
拥有更多的安全性。
But in our case, let's just go with one.
但是在我们的情况下，让我们与一个人一起去。
We are on testnet, and we are actually running out of time.
我们正在测试网上，实际上我们已经用完了。
Yeah, and now it's checkpoints in KingHoloshki, which might take a minute, but meanwhile,
是的，现在是Kingholoshki的检查站，可能需要一分钟，但同时
we can also execute get again, and we'll see what happens.
我们还可以再次执行获得，我们将看到会发生什么。
Okay, downloading the Genesis state, and get is, I don't have, I don't have, like, it's
好吧，下载创世纪状态，而我没有，我没有，就像
this vm i don't have like the pinning two sides i just want to show you the windows side to side
这个VM我不喜欢固定的两个侧面，我只想向您展示窗户的一边
this is terrible anyway okay get this looking for peers and um lighthouse
无论如何，这真是太可怕了
already loaded the checkpoint which is really nice
已经加载了检查站，这真的很好
so let's see if my computer will will manage
因此，让我们看看我的计算机是否会管理
it's not logging new things, which is, okay, something's happening. I'm not sure if my
它不是记录新事物，这是，正在发生的事情。我不确定我的
machine can handle this. Wait. What are we doing? CPU, anyway. Yeah, it should wake up
机器可以处理这个。等待。我们在做什么？ CPU，无论如何。是的，应该醒来
any moment execution point you see they are uh so they are uh successfully connected over the 8551
任何时刻的执行点，您都会看到它们是UH，因此它们在8551上成功连接
port uh endpoint uh they successfully authenticated because it loaded uh the latest
端口uh端点UH他们成功身份验证，因为它加载了最新的
timestamp of the blog there and uh yeah it the uh it cannot it cannot update uh the contract
那里的博客时间戳，嗯，是的，它不能更新合同
it's called drag info because it is not synced so they are kind of waiting for each other um
它称为拖放信息，因为它不是同步的，所以他们有点互相等待
uh get wants to find more peers for sure wait for it maybe um oh what's the what's the peer count
嗯，想找到更多的同行肯定等待，也许嗯，哦，什么是同行计数是什么
it's pretty short.
很短。
MaxPierce, right, yeah, don't remember that.
Maxpierce，对，是的，不记得了。
MaxPierce, it's three or something small, so it starts syncing sooner, it doesn't wait
maxpierce，是三个或小的东西，所以它早点开始同步，不等待
gather more peers. Just want to show you more what happens when you start thinking.
收集更多的同龄人。只想向您展示您开始思考时会发生什么。
Um, yeah. Yeah, my machine is kind of slow, so that's one thing, but let's look at our
嗯，是的。是的，我的机器有点慢，所以这是一回事，但是让我们看看我们的机器
outline for the workshop to see how are we doing okay something's happening okay
研讨会的概述，看看我们怎么做的好事
we are running and running on a family I wanted to demonstrate running on a
我们正在跑步和跑步，我想在一个家庭上演示
family because this needs to be done using the custom Genesis and it gives
家庭是因为需要使用自定义创世纪来完成此操作，并提供
you even more insight into like what the clients are actually doing and actually
您甚至更深入地了解客户实际在做什么，实际上
it might sync faster, because this doesn't look good.
它可能会更快地同步，因为这看起来不好。
Although, like you see, they are just fully connected.
虽然，就像您看到的那样，它们只是完全连接的。
They just need to wait a moment to wake up
他们只需要等待片刻才能醒来
to connect to the network, et cetera.
连接到网络等。
Yeah, to download the ephemer, to run ephemer,
是的，要下载Ephemer，以运行Ephemer，
let's go to ephemer.dev.
让我们去ephemer.dev。
Yeah, it's gonna kill it now.
是的，现在要杀死它。
Sorry, resources for all of you.
抱歉，所有人的资源。
Yeah, let's go to the project repository in the Genesis repository.
是的，让我们转到Genesis存储库中的项目存储库。
So here is like a general information about a testnet and in cloning.
因此，这就像有关测试网和克隆的一般信息。
Like it's restarting every week, so it's very small.
就像每周重新启动一样，所以很小。
It's like week worth of mostly empty chain data, so it can be synced
就像一周价值大部分是空链数据的价值，因此可以同步
very fast and very, very easily.
非常快，非常非常容易。
And here is an example how to get the node working.
这是如何使节点工作的示例。
You see it's very simple.
您会发现这很简单。
It's just an extra comment.
这只是一个额外的评论。
So let's start with that.
因此，让我们从此开始。
We need to first download the latest release, which I will put it here, but it goes straight
我们需要首先下载最新版本，我将其放在这里，但它直接直接
to releases.
发行。
So you see the 119.
因此，您会看到119。
9, this chain ID, this genesis time, let's download this net all, which is all the test
9，这个连锁ID，这个创世纪时间，让我们下载所有网络，这是所有测试
net data we can have. Okay, let's untar them. So it's download, and it's test net all, and
我们可以拥有的净数据。好吧，让我们解开它们。因此，它是下载的，并且是测试网的全部，并且
here we have, oh, it just un-played it right here, it's a mess. So here you see all the
哦，在这里，它只是在这里没有玩，这真是一团糟。所以在这里您看到了所有
different this is the fmr genesis data all you need to run fmr basically so to to read this
不同的是FMR Genesis数据，您基本上需要运行FMR，以阅读此内容
uh to see what's happening here uh the basic is the genesis json which defines
嗯，看看这里发生了什么，呃，基本是定义的创世纪JSON
the actual network uh so here it gives balances to different accounts like for
实际网络uh，因此在这里为不同的帐户提供余额
you know for initial users for for testers validate it for faucets yeah um
您知道初始用户的测试人员验证了水龙头的符合测试人员的um
Yeah, the difficulty, no extra data, timestamp of the Genesis importance, when the network actually starts.
是的，当网络真正启动时，难度，没有额外的数据，Genesis重要性的时间戳。
And to get on the top, you can also see the forks, all these accounts.
为了登顶，您还可以看到所有这些帐户。
Yeah, so here are the forks, which are all happening at zero.
是的，所以这里有叉子，它们都在零时发生。
Only the Shanghai and Cancun are later.
只有上海和坎昆以后。
Yeah.
是的。
So, this is basically the definition of a network.
因此，这基本上就是网络的定义。
But then, there is also more stuff you need to pick with this to be able to run it, like
但是，您还需要选择更多的东西才能运行它，就像
information about boot notes.
有关引导笔记的信息。
Which one is it?
它是哪一个？
So, these are the execution layer, boot notes, write, generalization of all data routes,
因此，这些是执行层，引导注释，写入，所有数据路由的概括，
the beacon state in this Genesis SSE, which Lighthouse will download it there.
该Genesis SSE中的Beacon State将在此下载它。
So we have it all downloaded here, and we can point our clients to it.
因此，我们在这里下载了所有这些，我们可以将客户指向它。
So to use get with this, it was running get here, on the Holoshki, and this time let's
因此，要使用此操作，它正在运行，在这里，在Holoshki上，这次让我们
point it to this test net.
将其指向此测试网。
And how we do it is that we need to let's make it direct through memory.
以及我们如何做到的是，我们需要让它通过记忆直接使其直接使其直接。
So first, we need to initialize the genesis.
因此，首先，我们需要初始化创世纪。
So we need get to write down this genesis in its database.
因此，我们需要在其数据库中写下此创世纪。
Oh, yeah, in here it's just an example.
哦，是的，在这里只是一个例子。
It should be fixed.
它应该修复。
There's an example with, like, the old release, but just go to the release page and use the
有一个示例，例如旧版本，但只需转到发布页面并使用
latest one.
最新一个。
I should fix that.
我应该解决这个问题。
It's a bad example, but it's confusing.
这是一个糟糕的例子，但令人困惑。
So we want to initialize the genesis, we do it with get init, but first we point it to
因此，我们想初始化创世纪，我们用init进行，但首先我们指出
the data deer.
数据鹿。
So let's use the data deer memory here.
因此，让我们在此处使用Data Deer内存。
And we want to init downloads, it's a JSON that I was showing you a moment ago.
我们想开始下载，这是我在片刻前向您展示的JSON。
And now, get creates the genesis state in this database.
现在，在此数据库中创建创世纪。
So now, in ffmary, we see that get initialized its data there.
因此，现在，在ffmary中，我们看到在此处将其数据初始化。
It's basically ready to run.
基本上准备运行。
The next thing, so all the variables, all the values, like iteration number, chain ID,
接下来的事情，因此所有变量，所有值，例如迭代号，链ID，
boot notes, blah, blah, blah, are in this values.
引导音符，等等，等等，等等。
So which in this, in this, um, in this document, so you, what you can
因此，在此文档中，在此中，您可以，您可以
easily do is source your shell to have these values right now, we know them.
我们知道它们现在很容易地采购您的外壳以拥有这些值。
So now we, we, you have it loaded in your shell so you can
所以现在我们，我们，您将其加载到外壳中，以便您可以
easily, easily run these commands.
轻松，轻松地运行这些命令。
Let's do again get with data-dir of the memory where we put it before.
让我们再次使用以前放置的内存数据仪。
And we need to tell them boot nodes, which is boot node, e-node, and I also want to add
我们需要告诉他们启动节点，这是引导节点，电子节点，我也想添加
the chain ID, just to be sure we have the right one.
链条ID，只是为了确保我们有正确的链条。
Okay, and it doesn't work.
好的，这行不通。
Ah, because chain ID is not defined.
啊，因为未定义链ID。
How do I...
我怎么...
Ah, it's not chain, it's network ID or something.
啊，它不是链，它是网络ID或其他内容。
Network ID, right, okay, my fault.
网络ID，对，好吧，我的错。
Network ID, okay, and now it's running.
网络ID，好的，现在正在运行。
Now we are running on this custom Genesis that we created and downloaded.
现在，我们正在使用我们创建和下载的这个自定义创世纪。
It's the ephemeris net.
这是埃弗默里斯网。
You see we are trying to, we already found two peers on ephemeris.
您会看到我们正在尝试，我们已经在埃弗默里斯（Ephemeris）上找到了两个同龄人。
That's great.
那太棒了。
Okay.
好的。
Now, meanwhile, in the Lighthouse land, let's do the same for Lighthouse.
同时，在灯塔土地上，让我们为灯塔做同样的事情。
Lighthouse has this beautiful dash testnet, so we can do, again, Lighthouse beacon node,
Lighthouse拥有这个美丽的仪表板测试网，因此我们可以做，灯塔信标节点，
and it has this flag for testnet, or you can short it to dash t,
它具有用于testnet的标志，或者您可以将其简短为dash t，
which lets me to point it to a directory with all of these values.
这使我可以将其指向所有这些值的目录。
I don't need to specify, like, oh, here is the genesis, here is the genesis state,
我不需要指定，就像，哦，这是创世纪，这是创世纪状态，
Here is the boot notes, it finds everything in the directory like this.
这是引导笔记，它可以找到类似目录中的所有内容。
So it's very, very, very easy.
因此，非常非常非常容易。
And the rest is the same.
其余的是相同的。
I'm just going to copy it.
我只是要复制它。
Okay.
好的。
We have something's happening for sure.
我们肯定会发生一些事情。
And it's syncing.
它是同步的。
This took a while on Holoshki.
这花了一段时间在Holoshki上。
Now it's happening faster.
现在，它发生的速度更快了。
I'm glad I could show you.
我很高兴能告诉你。
So yeah, again it's, yeah, get was looking for some peers.
是的，又是的，是的，正在寻找一些同龄人。
It found some that it can get the data from.
它发现了一些可以从中获取数据的东西。
And the same happened for Lighthouse that connected
连接的灯塔也发生了同样的事情
and wants to sync.
并想同步。
And now it's syncing in a way that you
现在，它以您的方式同步
see it can sync in a few minutes.
看到它可以在几分钟内同步。
It's amazing.
太神奇了。
it's super small and it's syncing so fast and it find out what is the what is the it it syncs to
它是超级小的，它的同步如此之快，并且发现它是什么是它同步的是什么
the current current or the uh the new uh new slot and then the fork choice dictates to get oh this
电流或uh新的UH新插槽，然后叉子选择决定获得哦
is the new head oh no this is the new head this is the new head this is the new head right it always
是新的头吗？
syncs to the next block and dictates to get where to sync from and it's also reading the
与下一个区块同步，并要求从哪里同步，也正在阅读
the data from the executions.
执行的数据。
So yeah, this can take a second, I guess,
是的，我想这可能需要一秒钟
but it's eventually going to sync.
但这最终将同步。
It's running.
它正在运行。
This ephemeris is very, very lightweight for it.
这个世代剧对此非常非常轻巧。
So like, LoadStart, for example, you
因此，例如，LoadStart，您
can use it on ephemera without downloading Genesis, anything.
可以在无需下载Genesis的情况下使用它。
It just runs because it's hard-coded in there.
它之所以运行，是因为它在那里进行了硬编码。
The other clients have not included it yet.
其他客户尚未包括在内。
OK, so we have nine minutes.
好，所以我们有9分钟。
This is basically the longest it can take to sync ephemeris.
基本上，这是同步世袭所需的时间最长。
It's the worst time, because the network is restarting
这是最糟糕的时间，因为网络正在重新启动
in like one or two hours.
在大约一个或两个小时。
So it's like one week minus one, two hours worth of data.
因此，这就像一周的一个星期，价值两个小时的数据。
But if I do this in like two hours,
但是，如果我在两个小时内这样做，
it's going to sync in a second, because it will be fresh work.
它将在一秒钟内同步，因为这将是新的工作。
So yeah, you can see here it's at.
是的，您可以在这里看到它。
Here, 19-00-UTC, we started it for, I think, right?
在这里，19-00-UTC，我们为此开始了，对吗？
So, yeah.
所以，是的。
Okay, so that's that.
好吧，就是这样。
So, now we have ephemera running.
因此，现在我们正在运行ephemera。
Let's talk to the node.
让我们与节点交谈。
Oh, now I'm wondering if I enabled HTTP here.
哦，现在我想知道我是否在这里启用了HTTP。
I didn't, right?
我没有，对吧？
Okay, let's do that.
好吧，让我们去做吧。
We want HTTP as well, so we can use it.
我们也需要HTTP，因此我们可以使用它。
Because I want to show you how you actually communicate with the client.
因为我想向您展示您如何实际与客户沟通。
For that, the good start is JSON, or like, also the client documentation is pretty good,
为此，良好的开始是JSON，或者是客户文档非常好，
or the JSONRPC in the, um, it's also good docs, but get, let's do it, like, let's do
或jsonrpc，嗯，这也是很好的文档，但是让我们去做，就像，让我们去做
more client-specific. Oh my god, this is syncing so slow. Oh, we can also checkpoint sync ephemera.
更特定于客户的。哦，天哪，这是如此慢。哦，我们还可以检查点同步ephemera。
There's a checkpoint sync provider for ephemera, which would make it faster, I guess. Maybe we can
我想有一个Epphemera的检查站同步提供商，这将使它更快。也许我们可以
do that. Is it deteriorating when I'm running the node, by the way? Is it dying or something?
这样做。顺便说一句，当我运行节点时它会恶化吗？是死亡还是什么？
it's worse than I'm syncing the node.
比我同步节点还要糟糕。
But here, checkpointsync, you see, we can use this website, which hopefully works, yeah,
但是在这里，CheckpointSync，您会看到，我们可以使用此网站，希望有效，是的，
to checkpointsync it.
要检查点。
So what do we want to do here is, I just go up to this, checkpointsync-url, it's checkpointsync-sync-sync,
所以我们想在这里做什么，我只是去这个checkpointsync-url，它是checkpointsync-sync-sync，
Checkpoint sync URL.
检查点同步URL。
Right here it says checkpoint-center-dash-URL.
就在这里，它说了检查点中心 - 划带。
That's this one.
那就是这个。
And now it's going to comply.
现在它将遵守。
No it's not going to comply.
不，这不会遵守。
It works.
有用。
But it's refusing to check point sync because we need to progdb first.
但这是拒绝检查点同步的，因为我们需要先进行progDB。
You see?
你看？
If you already started the big node, then you cannot just skip to checkpoint sync, because
如果您已经启动了大节点，那么您就不能只是跳过检查点同步，因为
you need to delete the existing database first.
您需要首先删除现有数据库。
So we are going to do that, and it will be even faster.
因此，我们将要这样做，它将更快。
Let's try this.
让我们尝试一下。
And we have the HTTP for communication on 8545.
我们拥有8545上的HTTP通信。
And this one, it's too light.
而且这太轻了。
OK, awesome.
好，很棒。
What I want to show you is the communication first
我想向您展示的是首先交流
over Coral, simply C-O-R-O.
在珊瑚上，只需C-O-R-O。
Is there some examples here?
这里有一些例子吗？
Come on, there should be examples.
来吧，应该有例子。
So, yeah, it call, it's simple, it's called create access list, nope, okay, it's good
所以，是的，它叫，很简单，称为创建访问列表，不，好，很好，很好
This is just the domain, the name specific.
这只是域，名称是特定的。
But yeah, here, this is a good documentation with examples.
但是，是的，这是一个很好的文档，其中包含示例。
So you can see all the different,
因此，您可以看到所有不同的
all the different,
所有不同，
oh, come on.
哦，来吧。
Yeah, we can just use this,
是的，我们可以使用它，
and you can see all the different,
您可以看到所有不同的
all the different,
所有不同，
it's missing the headers actually it's not fully correct because what you want to do
它实际上缺少标题，因为您想做的事，这并不完全正确
it's for sure post but you want to have a header that it's content type location slash
可以肯定的是帖子，但您想拥有一个标题，它是内容类型的位置斜杠
it might probably want to answer.
它可能想回答。
And now the, what are we requesting here?
现在，我们在这里要求什么？
The data, let's copy it here.
数据，让我们在这里复制它。
Yeah, sorry, I'm not used to the environment
是的，对不起，我不习惯环境
because it's just a pressure VM
因为这只是压力VM
And I want to go localhost h.
我想去Local主持h。
No.
不。
Okay, and we see that it,
好吧，我们看到了，
the protocol version method is not supported,
不支持协议版方法，
but it answered, that's great, it answered.
但是它回答了，太好了，它回答了。
I don't know why this is not supported,
我不知道为什么不支持这一点，
which is funny,
这很有趣，
but we can ask about the syncing state, for example.
但是，例如，我们可以询问同步状态。
it's not syncing, it's synced already, it's synced, it's synced, it's synced, it's synced,
它不是同步的，已经同步了，已同步，已同步，已同步，已同步，
it's synced, it's synced, it's synced, it's synced, it's synced, it's synced, it's synced,
它是同步的，已同步，已同步，已同步，已同步，已同步，已同步，
yeah yeah we see we are we are synced now it's getting just the historical blocks uh the current
是的，是的，我们看到我们已经同步了，它只是获得了历史障碍，吗
state is achieved because we checkpoint sync so now it goes backwards uh it's lighthouse and you
状态之所以实现，是因为我们检查点同步了，所以现在它向后往后走，嗯，你是灯塔
see um get here is happily important importing every 12 seconds new blocks so it's it's happening
看到UM到达这里很重要一次，每12秒进口新块，所以它正在发生
we don't have many peers maybe because i'm in the vm on like random internet but yeah it's uh
我们可能没有很多同行，因为我像随机互联网一样在VM上，但是是的
The chain had updated every 12 seconds, so it's following the current state.
该连锁店每12秒更新一次，因此它遵循当前状态。
So it's not syncing.
因此，它不是同步。
That was right.
没错。
I was expecting it will tell me, like, you know, what is the current head, and it's syncing
我期望它会告诉我，就像，你知道，当前的头是什么，它正在同步
and so on.
等等。
But it didn't happen.
但这没有发生。
Let's use some other it.
让我们使用其他一些。
We can ask just, like, for the block number, for example, right?
例如，我们可以对块号询问，例如，对吗？
So here I ask him the block number, and this is the current block number in hex.
因此，我在这里问他块号，这是十六进制中的当前块号。
So you get these answers from the JSONRPC with the values are mostly encoded in hexadecimal
因此，您可以从jsonrpc获得这些答案，其中大部分是在十六进制中编码的
format, it can easily decode this, and it should correspond to the current fmbrhead.
格式，它可以轻松地解码此问题，并且应与当前的FMBRHEAD相对应。
So yeah, this is how you use the core role to talk to it.
是的，这就是您使用核心角色与之交谈的方式。
Of course, this can be in so many different packages.
当然，这可能是在许多不同的软件包中。
You can have it as a Python package in Web3Pi.
您可以将其作为Web3PI中的Python软件包。
It's mostly used, this communication with this RPC
它主要使用，与此RPC的通信
is mostly used in, this URL is good for maybe
大多用于使用，此URL适合可能
bash scripts or something that you want to quickly check.
bash脚本或您想快速检查的内容。
But in reality, you use the Web3Pi
但实际上，您使用web3pi
with something like Ethers.js on the dApps, right?
在Dapps上的Ethers.js之类的东西，对吗？
Or in the backend in Python or so on,
或在Python的后端，依此类推，
or you use some already existing tooling,
或者您使用一些已经存在的工具，
which makes it easier and wraps all these answers,
这使它变得更容易并包裹所有这些答案，
so you don't need to manually read all the fields
因此，您无需手动阅读所有字段
and transpile it from different coding or something.
并从不同的编码或其他内容中转移它。
Also, you can use this, of course, in your wallet.
另外，您当然可以在钱包中使用它。
So let's maybe do that.
因此，让我们这样做。
I have a metamask here that I installed for this purpose, doing a workshop.
我在这里安装了一个元掩体，为此目的进行了研讨会。
And it has some default, Ethereum mainnet, whatnot, but we can switch to, okay, blah,
它有一些默认的以太坊主网，什么，但是我们可以切换到，好吧，等等
blah, blah, blah, blah.
等等，等等，等等。
Yeah, I want to switch network, add network.
是的，我想切换网络，添加网络。
So here I want to add network, which is going to point to my own, oh, wait, there's some
因此，在这里我想添加网络，这将指向我自己的网络，哦，等等，有一些
questions, I'm sorry.
问题，对不起。
I'm running best on tech on Mac, nice.
我在Mac上的Tech上运行最佳，不错。
Yeah, if you need help, we will get to that in the end.
是的，如果您需要帮助，我们最终会做到这一点。
Yeah, add network manually.
是的，手动添加网络。
So, we are doing HTTP localhost, this is where it wants the chain ID, it could not fetch,
因此，我们正在做HTTP Localhost，这是它想要的链ID的地方，它无法获取，
it's fine.
很好。
Is the RPC correct?
RPC正确吗？
Did it kill it or something?
它杀死了吗？
No.
不。
Maybe I need to allow it.
也许我需要允许它。
So let's try a different RPC.
因此，让我们尝试不同的RPC。
So let's test whether it's, it's not nice.
因此，让我们测试它是否不好。
So what you might want to do in this case
因此，在这种情况下，您可能想做的
is to kill get and look into the help for the HTTP, yeah,
是要杀死get＆查看HTTP的帮助，是的，
course domain.
课程域。
Yeah, so maybe we want to do the query domain or vhosts just
是的，所以也许我们想做查询域或vhost
to make sure that this might be the problem.
确保这可能是问题。
OK, I'm wondering, I'm wondering.
好的，我想知道，我想知道。
But it should work.
但这应该起作用。
I don't know if this always worked.
我不知道这是否总是有效。
I don't know if it's the chain ID.
我不知道这是否是连锁ID。
Localhost it.
Localhost。
What am I doing?
我在做什么？
The mistake, guys.
错误，伙计们。
Come on, come on, help me fix this.
来吧，来吧，帮助我解决这个问题。
This is gonna work.
这会起作用。
What do I want to do?
我想做什么？
Instead...
反而...
Maybe I want to do it instead of 5, maybe?
也许我想这样做，而不是5？
That's too bad.
太糟糕了。
Okay.
好的。
Okay, let's see.
好吧，让我们看看。
What's your problem?
你有什么问题？
Shut up.
住口。
it doesn't it doesn't it won't work this is weird it's not nice i think it's in my wallet
它不是不起作用，这很奇怪，这不是很好，我认为它在我的钱包里
i'm very mad now i don't know why it says this is happening oh my god guys any any tips any
我现在很生气，现在我不知道为什么会说这发生了
tips and tricks maybe we can try a different wallet but it always worked like this in metamask
提示和窍门，也许我们可以尝试其他钱包，但它总是在MetAmask中像这样起作用
I wonder what's stopping me here.
我想知道是什么阻止了我。
What was the chain ID?
什么是链条ID？
It should fetch it by itself, right?
它本身应该拿走，对吗？
Because you can just ask.
因为你可以问。
And we just did it in the other window, right?
我们只是在另一个窗口中做到了，对吗？
Let me try again, it will show you it block number works, it's localhost 8 5 4 5, which
让我再试一次，它将向您显示块数字有效，是Localhost 8 5 4 5，
is also correct.
也正确。
So I don't know.
所以我不知道。
What's due to be shame ID, which is correct.
是什么是羞耻的ID，这是正确的。
OK, that's not nice, because I can reach it over crawl,
好的，那不是很好，因为我可以通过爬行到达
but I can't reach it in metamask for some reason.
但是由于某种原因，我无法在Metamask中达到它。
Maybe there is something I'm missing, maybe there's some browser settings or something.
也许我缺少一些东西，也许有一些浏览器设置或其他东西。
Yeah it's such an idiotic to have a browser wallet anyway but, okay I don't know, I'm
是的，无论如何都有浏览器钱包真是个愚蠢的
so sorry guys, I'm so disappointed right now, I'm not sure how to, let's add ephemera here.
很抱歉，我现在很失望，我不确定如何，让我们在这里添加ephemera。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的。
Let's add ephemera here.
让我们在这里添加ephemera。
Ah this is disappointing, this is too bad.
啊，这是令人失望的，这太糟糕了。
This is the public RPC, but it's still fine.
这是公共RPC，但仍然很好。
Yeah.
是的。
Maybe there is some extra conflict that I need,
也许我需要一些额外的冲突，
but I did this so many times, and I think that all I needed
但是我做了很多次，我认为我需要的一切
was just this.
只是这个。
And I actually have my own node running, but it's
我实际上有自己的节点运行，但这是
missing some headers.
缺少一些标题。
But it should work.
但这应该起作用。
It should work.
它应该起作用。
I don't know it's it's missing some stupid conflict I think like we have the
我不知道这是缺少一些愚蠢的冲突，我认为我们有
course of sorry this is it's lighthouse
对不起，这是灯塔
um yeah we've been running it here yeah maybe the course domain is wrong or or
嗯，我们一直在这里运行它，是的，也许课程域是错误的或
something like that
这样的东西
dot uh oh my god what is the address
哦，哦，天哪，地址是什么
all interfaces
所有接口
okay nice uh maybe now let's go to one more try just because i'm
好的，很好，也许现在让我们再尝试一次，因为我
getting nervous and curious and it's a search it's upon you
变得紧张和好奇，这是一个搜索
I hope you learn something so fast.
希望您学到这么快的东西。
Yeah.
是的。
Oh, this is good.
哦，这很好。
Yeah, the course version needs to be from the Chrome extension.
是的，课程版本需要来自Chrome扩展名。
Oh, that's so ugly.
哦，太丑了。
But let's try it.
但是让我们尝试一下。
Let's try it.
让我们尝试一下。
OK, let's add a custom network again.
好的，让我们再次添加一个自定义网络。
And yeah, now I want Moz extension, which is this one.
是的，现在我想要Moz Extension，这就是一个。
So should I just use this in the course domain?
那么我应该在课程域中使用它吗？
Okay, let's try it.
好吧，让我们尝试一下。
Let's try it again.
让我们再试一次。
Maybe.
或许。
Ah, now it's working.
啊，现在正在工作。
So okay, I did a wild card.
好吧，我做了一张通配符。
That's probably the worst idea.
那可能是最糟糕的主意。
um yeah and it's currently it won't let me connect because it's currently in use because i already
嗯，是的，目前它不会让我连接，因为它目前正在使用，因为我已经
added the network before okay now it works it calms me down but yeah uh this comes me down but
现在添加了网络，现在可以工作它使我平静下来，但是是的，这让我失望了，但是
yeah i what i had to do as you can see is like to enable to put the wild card uh yeah what it is i
是的，我所能看到的，我要做的就是要放置通配符嗯，是的
it instead of specifying the most extensions whatnot i did um wild card for the course domain
它没有指定最多的扩展名，我为课程域做了um通配符
which you shouldn't do guys wildcard for hosts and also i'm running on all interface instead
您不应该为主机做通配符的人，而我也在所有界面上运行
of local hosts it's running on all available interfaces including the local host of course but
在本地主机中，它正在运行在包括本地主机在内的所有可用接口上，但是
uh this is something you shouldn't do any i'm doing this because it's in a vm and i don't mind
嗯，这是您不应该做的事情，因为它在VM中，我不介意
but you shouldn't do this in a you know uh serious setup um yeah maybe let's change it to localhost
但是您不应该在知道认真的设置中这样做
just by killing this and i wonder if the course domains uh themselves will help it's an interesting
只是杀死这一点，我想知道课程域是否会帮助它是一个有趣的
that's interesting piece of knowledge for sure add network again annually it's this x where it
这是有趣的知识，肯定每年再次添加网络，这是x
it works. So it's the core domains that I set to the wildcard. So yeah, thank you so
有用。因此，这是我设置在通配符上的核心域。是的，谢谢你
much, Meldzden. It was exactly what you said with the Bessu. It was it was the core domain
很多，梅尔兹登。这正是您对Bessu所说的。这是核心领域
issue. So it's like it's a security feature that it doesn't let you to, you know, connect
问题。因此，这就像是一个安全功能，它不允许您连接
to your node from some random string interfaces
从某些随机字符串接口到您的节点
or something like that.
或类似的东西。
There is something more that I wanted to show you
我想向你展示更多的东西
with a memory, and that's like running also
有记忆，就像运行一样
the Validator part.
验证器部分。
Let's see the workshop.
让我们看看车间。
Okay, we can maybe, yeah, x, we did this,
好吧，我们也许可以，是的，x，我们做到了，
or maybe also the console.
或者也许也是控制台。
So there is one thing on get you can do,
所以有一件事可以做到，
and it's get attach, you need to have data,
它是附件的，您需要拥有数据，
here it was ephemery right and now we are in the console so instead of using corel
在这里，它是ephemery，现在我们在控制台中，所以不使用corel
i can just talk to him directly right like oh tell me your peers here are all the peers i'm
我只能像他直接与他交谈，就像哦，告诉我你的同龄人，这是我的所有同龄人
connected to etc so this is one one one little thing i wanted to show you as well this it might
连接到等，所以这是我想向你展示的一件小事。
be practical like to like for example connect your node so what you what you can do is go to
例如，要像喜欢连接您的节点一样实用，所以您可以做的就是去
ethernets.io and here you see bunch of different nodes you can even check ephemery nodes
ethernets.io，在这里，您可以看到许多不同的节点，甚至可以检查Ephemery节点
the current iteration and here uh in help you find the um uh these are all the instances of
当前的迭代和这里的帮助您在帮助您找到这些都是所有实例
the peer-to-peer client that it's running so you can choose one of these and add it
它正在运行的点对点客户端，因此您可以选择其中之一并添加
it as a peer, you see? So I'm going to connect. Now I edit a peer of this eNote. I just edit
它是同伴，你知道吗？所以我要连接。现在，我编辑了此Enote的同行。我只是编辑
a note to connect to. It edits it to a QE, and at one point, get will try connect to
通知的注释。它将其编辑为量化宽度
it, and it will help to maybe discover more peers and whatnot. And then when I go to stats
它，这将有助于发现更多的同龄人等。然后当我去统计
and i look at it or when i go to the notes part and uh you can you can see the latest latest notes
我看着它，或者当我转到笔记部分时，嗯，您可以看到最新的笔记
and uh okay this is if i know that you can see all the information about it what not so if you if you
嗯，好的，这是我知道您可以看到所有有关它的信息
then connect to this crawler you can read all these values by yourself it's nice nice way to
然后连接到这个轨道，您可以自己阅读所有这些值，这是很好的好方法
make sure that uh you see that uh it's uh it yeah so in this case the crawler was dialing this node
确保您看到它是嗯，是的
instead of the other way so you can make for example make sure that like the dialing to your
而不是另一种方式，以便您可以确保像拨打与您的拨号一样
node is okay etc so that's something you can you can do after but yeah one thing how to add peers
节点还可以，所以这是您可以做的事情，但是是的一件事如何添加同行
it's like using the console because what you want to do is like you know don't have the this is
就像使用控制台一样，因为您想做的就是您知道没有这个
using the ipc this is using um as it said before this is trying using this ipc file as a communication
在此之前，使用IPC使用的是使用UM尝试使用此IPC文件作为通信
with node so what you can have is like only engine eat i know net takes cool web 3 just like these
有了节点，您可以拥有的就是只有引擎吃，我知道网络会像这样的网络3
safe safe um uh namespaces enabled on your normal node and then through ipc you can also connect to
安全的安全UM UH uh uh umh命名空间在您的普通节点上启用，然后通过IPC连接到
admin and uh yeah handle your node so it's an example of this well i mean you don't have
admin和uh是的，处理您的节点，所以这是一个很好的例子
to trust because you can verify their data so uh this and these are not notes what i was showing
信任，因为您可以验证他们的数据，所以呃，这些不是我所显示的
it's just like instance of the crawler it's just to get get so they can gather your data more easily
就像爬网的实例一样，它只是为了获取，以便他们可以更轻松地收集您的数据
so now uh let's do a little poll what do you feel like switching a client or we can maybe go to the
所以现在嗯，让我们进行一些民意调查，您想切换客户或我们可以转到
validator it's like one lot we are we are over 90 minutes now and the validator was one last thing i
验证器就像我们现在已经超过90分钟了，验证器是我的最后一件事
wanted to show you i'm not sure if i can but let's look into it like it's easiest on a film
想向你展示我不确定我是否可以，但让我们像电影上最简单的那样研究它
let's do it quickly uh let's go to launchpad let's go to here and let's go to offset okay
让我们快速去做吧，让我们去启动板，让我们去这里，让我们去抵消还可以的
first let's get some money from the fall so it's easy i don't need to teach you that
首先，让我们从秋天那里得到一些钱，所以很容易我不需要教你
it. Ah, it just loads. Okay. Address here. Thank you. We have it. And if we want to become
它。啊，它只是加载。好的。地址在这里。谢谢。我们有。如果我们想成为
validated, we need to learn all the important things. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. Don't do it.
经过验证，我们需要学习所有重要的东西。是的，是的，是的。不要做。
Read it. Especially if you are using main app. But now I just want to show you how to
阅读。特别是如果您使用的是主应用程序。但是现在我只想告诉你如何
the deposit and uh this is actually also a good knowledge source like the staking um staking
存款和嗯，这实际上也是一个很好的知识来源
launchpad gives you some nice information about the different clients about uh all the
LaunchPad为您提供了有关不同客户的一些很好的信息
responsibilities as a validator and the configuration i'm going to like skip this
作为验证器的责任和我喜欢跳过的配置
because we know all of that and um here it tells you how to generate the keys so yeah this is
因为我们知道所有这些，嗯，它告诉您如何生成钥匙，所以是的
something i want to show you uh so the way that ethereum validator works is that uh it's using
我想向您展示的东西，以太坊验证器的工作方式是它正在使用
some sort of um private key to uh sign the attestation data or publish the new new blog
某种UM私有键可以签署证明数据或发布新博客
you need to you need to sign this with your key you deposit 32 it uh to the deposit contract
您需要用钥匙签名
the deposit contract is the uh it's the it's the richest one on ethereum right um
存款合同是在以太坊上的最富有的合同
and you deposit you deposit um uh um your transaction in there
然后您将您的交易存入其中
uh which then activates your volator so you see that this is the deposit contract you can read
嗯，然后激活您的Volator，因此您会看到这是您可以阅读的存款合同
the code here and you always make sure that you interact on mainnet with this contract on on um
这里的代码，您始终确保您在Mainnet上与此合同上的互动
So, on ephemery or test nets it's on different address, like 4242 something.
因此，在Ephemery或测试网上，它在不同的地址上，例如4242。
If you are using Windows or something, you can use like a GUI like this, but we can simply
如果您使用的是Windows之类的东西，则可以像这样的GUI使用，但是我们可以简单地使用
generate keys using this terminal.
使用此终端生成密钥。
it. I downloaded the staking deposit CLI. So let's open it. And here we have this feature
它。我下载了存放存款CLI。因此，让我们打开它。在这里我们有这个功能
called deposit. And we can either have it with existing or new mnemonics. You need to
称为存款。我们可以使用现有的或新的助记符。你需要
make a passphrase first. Let's do it as a new one. And this lets you generate the keys
首先制作一个密码。让我们作为新的做。这使您可以生成钥匙
to import to your validator and then run it.
要导入您的验证器，然后运行它。
Let's run it.
让我们运行它。
And we want it in this case it's important.
在这种情况下，我们希望它很重要。
We need password.
我们需要密码。
Okay, we need to write it down.
好的，我们需要写下来。
It's good to write it down even on test nets.
即使在测试网上也写下来也是一件好事。
It happened to me, I was running it and I lost it.
它发生在我身上，我正在运行它，我丢失了它。
I couldn't recover them and I had to deposit again it's annoying so yeah you want to
我无法恢复它们，我不得不再次存入它很烦人，所以你想
check the keys and now we have keys that we are ready to activate using
检查钥匙，现在我们有了可以使用的密钥，可以使用
using the deposit okay so yeah it was data so the deposit data informs the website about
使用押金可以，是的，是的是数据，因此存款数据将信息告知网站
the data uh about our validator public keys uh that are going to the contract and it's going to
有关我们将要签订合同的验证器公共密钥的数据，它将
help us to make the transaction um so this is like a um it's like an easy way to walk through it yes
帮助我们进行交易嗯，这就像一个嗯，就像是一种简单的漫步方式
okay we have a 32 fm array test that's one validator i understand i understand i understand
好吧，我们有一个32 FM阵列测试，这是我了解我了解的一个验证器
uh it's good to i'm going it doing it fast but you can read through this to understand
嗯，我要快速进行它是一件好事，但是您可以阅读此信息以了解
and the stake is taking much better.
而且赌注要好得多。
And let's go to deposit.
让我们去存款。
What I want to show you is that how you then import the,
我想向您展示的是您如何导入，
oh, wait, I have 30 to eat, but I need more
哦，等等，我有30个吃饭，但我需要更多
because there are fees, right?
因为有费用，对吗？
Of course, there are fees.
当然，有费用。
Where's the deposit again?
存款再次在哪里？
Okay, one more time.
好吧，再一次。
I need the address again.
我再次需要地址。
okay this is actually good point I need to change it to 38 or something
好吧，这实际上是我需要将其更改为38的好点。
here we go okay again
在这里，我们又走了
it still didn't bind the previous transaction, hopefully.
希望它仍然没有约束以前的交易。
Okay so this is mostly it.
好的，所以主要是这样。
So we do deposit now, just the deposit, and now the beacon here, you will see it in a
因此，我们现在已经存款，只是存款，现在的灯塔在这里，您会在
second, that there is a new validator waiting for, so the problem is that now we have to
其次，有一个新的验证器在等待，所以问题是现在我们必须
wait, and wait a second.
等待，等一下。
So it takes hours to activate the validator on the network.
因此，激活网络上的验证器需要数小时。
Yeah, you see it's in the QE.
是的，您看到它在量化宽松中。
It was done 43 seconds ago, and it takes 16 to 20.
它是在43秒前完成的，需要16至20。
So in the lifetime of this test it won't happen, because it's going to be inactive.
因此，在此测试的一生中，它不会发生，因为它将不活动。
it's going it's so it's been pending until it will die so we don't yeah we don't want to activate
它是这样的，所以一直待定直到它死了，所以我们不想激活我们不想激活
this but i want to show you this but still uh i want to show you the follow-up now when we have
这个，但我想向你展示，但我仍然想向你展示我们的后续行动
we have those keys and let's pretend we are waiting for the activation um
我们有那些钥匙，让我们假装我们正在等待激活
so we go to lighthouse and this time we want to run the valid client oh but before that we need
所以我们去灯塔，这次我们想运行有效的客户哦，但在我们需要之前
to import the data, so we need to import the keys that we used.
要导入数据，因此我们需要导入使用的密钥。
So let's do account manager, import from data deer it's data lighthouse here.
因此，让我们做客户经理，从数据鹿中导入它的数据灯塔。
Yeah, lhdata, okay.
是的，lhdata，好的。
With the testnet pointing to the memory, which is sadly in the downloads.
测试网指向内存，可悲的是下载中。
it's been a mess.
真是一团糟。
The directory puts us to the actual
目录使我们进入了实际
Validated keys file.
验证的键文件。
it wasn't expected okay oh i need to do it okay now i put the password so what you want to what
没想到好吧，哦，我需要做的好，现在我输入密码，所以您想要什么
you want to do if you have like thousands of validators of course is to create a
当然，如果您有成千上万的验证者，您想做的是创建一个
file or just reuse the password uh like there's a there's a feature for that if you're doing like
文件或仅重复使用密码，嗯，如果您做的话，有一个功能
big texting but now we import it to the lighthouse database we have the validators uh validators here
大约发短信，但现在我们将其导入灯塔数据库，我们在此处拥有验证器UH
So you see it's the public key, and we are now able to run the lighthouse also.
因此，您会看到它是公钥，现在我们也能够运行灯塔。
I mean, you can always just run the validator, but it's not going to help anything.
我的意思是，您始终可以运行验证器，但这不会有帮助。
So now we need to run it as an actual valid client.
因此，现在我们需要将其作为实际有效客户端运行。
So again, we want to use the t for download, so we need the data here, which is lhdata,
因此，再次，我们要使用t进行下载，因此我们需要这里的数据，即lhdata，
and I think it could be it.
我认为可能是。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Wait, wait, it's going to be Knote, why?
等待，等等，这将是knote，为什么？
Why?
为什么？
I didn't enable the HTTP on BKnote?
我没有在bknote上启用HTTP？
I did.
我做到了。
Oh, I did it.
哦，我做到了。
Okay, so of course, the validator is connecting to the beacon node using the HTTP endpoint.
好的，当然，验证器使用HTTP端点连接到信标节点。
So it needs to be enabled.
因此需要启用它。
And you see here it's connected to the beacon node.
而且您在这里看到它已连接到信标节点。
Here it's connected to the beacon node, flushing protection.
在这里，它连接到浮游保护的信标节点。
And it's awaiting activation.
它正在等待激活。
So you see it's going to take a while to activate.
因此，您会看到要激活需要一段时间。
it's something that you want to always set up if you are running Validator.
如果您正在运行验证器，这是您想要始终设置的东西。
Do I have it?
我有吗？
No.
不。
I don't have it.
我没有。
So, set up your address as the, as the, as a fee recipient, and now we are successfully
因此，将您的地址设置为作为收费收件人的地址，现在我们已经成功
during the validator. I'm so sorry, I can't show you the stations, it's going to take
在验证器期间。很抱歉，我无法向您展示电台，这将需要
a while for this to deposit. If I'm clever enough, I would deposit it before the workshop,
一段时间以存入。如果我足够聪明，我会将其存放在研讨会之前，
and I actually did this morning, but it still didn't activate. So yeah, this is the best
实际上，我今天早上做了，但它仍然没有激活。是的，这是最好的
I can do right now. Yeah, you see it's back to the beacon node and it's just waiting,
我现在可以做。是的，您看到它又回到了信标节点，它正在等待，
so now the validator client is sitting and waiting while the beacon node is checking
因此，现在验证器客户端正在坐着和等待信标节点检查
as it get this dragon uh importing new blocks and finally the beacon node is complaining that
因为它得到了这条龙的导入新块，最后灯塔节点抱怨
it has only one pair it's not nice it should be work but yeah let's see it and i'm going to kill
它只有一对不好
it now because we don't need it anymore but yeah this was a family this was this was the memory uh
现在因为我们不再需要它，但是是的，这是一个家庭，这就是记忆
the ephemera setup okay uh also with validators so yeah uh we are at almost two hours i think
ephemera设置还可以，呃，嗯，是的，是的，我想我们要在将近两个小时
i think that's more than enough and i don't see any questions in discord
我认为这还远远不够，我看不到任何问题
oh uh so no it's not going to be uh activated in the next epoch it's going to be
哦，呃，不，在下一个时代不会被激活
activated like in many many epochs uh which is looking to the execution sorry the consensus specs
像在许多时期一样被激活，uh uh正在寻找执行，对不起，共识规格
where it's explained well the activation period, look for the activation period, which depends
在激活周期很好地解释的地方，寻找激活期，这取决于
on how many validators are in the queue, it depends, but for now it's gonna be too long to
关于队列中有多少验证者，这取决于
wait for that, and I was checking the validators from the morning it was like eight hours ago,
等待那个
and it's all not active yet, I should have done it yesterday, I'm sorry.
这一切还不是活跃，我应该昨天做到，对不起。
it.
它。
Yeah, anyway, please let me know if you have any questions.
是的，无论如何，如果您有任何疑问，请告诉我。
If you have something else you would like to have me demonstrate, we discussed the environment
如果您还有其他想法，您想让我演示，我们讨论了环境
and the clients.
和客户。
We get the clients through the binary, and we compiled it.
我们通过二进制来吸引客户，然后进行了编译。
We didn't do Docker, but if you want to do it, you can do it.
我们没有做Docker，但是如果您想这样做，可以做到。
you can write your own Docker script or just use the official it's very easy you just do
您可以编写自己的Docker脚本，也可以使用官员，这很容易您只需
docker run.
Docker Run。
What is more problematic with the Docker setup is that you need to know how to handle the
Docker设置更有问题的是您需要知道如何处理
ports and the networking, whether you want to run it as a host mode or you want to create
端口和网络，无论您要以主机模式运行还是要创建它
a custom network, for example, when you are connecting to different clients, it's best
例如，当您连接到不同客户端时，它是最好的
it in some Compose file.
它在某些撰写文件中。
So yes, it's like some thing on the Docker.
所以，是的，就像码头机上的一些事情。
As it's a custom Genesis, we did that.
由于这是一个自定义的创世纪，我们做到了。
We didn't try different clients.
我们没有尝试不同的客户。
We should try some other clients.
我们应该尝试其他一些客户。
I suggested Nimbus and Erigon for reasons
我建议Nimbus和Erigon的原因
that Nimbus is very lightweight, and I
尼布斯非常轻巧，我
knew that it's going to be a problem on my low hardware
知道这将是我低硬件上的问题
here.
这里。
And also Erigon is interesting from the perspective.
从这个角度来看，埃里贡也很有趣。
The Ergon is interesting from the perspective of the way it syncs.
从其同步的角度来看，埃尔贡很有趣。
Like it has the stage sync, and it has interesting logs about what is happening in this moment.
就像它具有舞台同步，并且有关此刻正在发生的事情的有趣日志。
So you can actually see this different paradigm of syncing, which is also using red.
因此，您实际上可以看到这种不同的同步范式，它也使用红色。
We accessed the RPC, we used validators, and I didn't get to systemd setup, but maybe we
我们访问了RPC，我们使用了验证器，但我没有进入SystemD设置，但是也许我们
can do it later.
可以稍后再做。
Now, if you feel like continuing, we can go to EPFSG workshop.
现在，如果您想继续前进，我们可以去EPFSG研讨会。
This is okay.
没关系。
It's a good link.
这是一个很好的链接。
Anyway, here, we can meet here.
无论如何，在这里，我们可以在这里见面。
If you want to continue, we'll come to this GT and off recording, we can do some more exercises.
如果您想继续，我们将来到此GT并关闭录音，我们可以做更多的练习。
is if you have any you know troubles with your stuff you can you can uh screen share and i can
是，如果您有任何东西，您知道自己的东西，您可以分享屏幕，我可以
ask you some you can ask me some questions i can do some troubleshooting but also you know if you
问你一些你可以问我一些问题，我可以做一些故障排除，但你知道你是否
have any other questions like go ahead um the iterations of ephemera that's that's one week
还有其他任何问题，例如继续前进的临时迭代，这是一周
right now we're going to make it one month uh but right now it's weekly from thursday evening
现在，我们要做一个月的嗯，但是现在是星期四晚上的每周
or Thursday evening. How do I look at the transaction mempool? So yeah, you're using
或星期四晚上。我如何看交易孟买？是的，你正在使用
the RPC, as I was showing in the Ethereum board, JSON-RPC. This one is the best documentation
RPC，正如我在以太坊董事会所展示的JSON-RPC一样。这是最好的文档
if you want to see all the different calls pretty well explained.
如果您想查看所有不同的电话，都可以很好地解释。
So, yeah, if you want to see blobs, you need to use the Beacon API.
所以，是的，如果您想查看斑点，则需要使用信标API。
Those are on the...
那些在...
Yep, this one.
是的，这个。
So, for blobs, you can read blob per slot.
因此，对于斑点，您可以读取每个插槽的斑点。
in... not events... in... no?
在...不是事件...中...不？
no, it's it... wait it doesn't open?
不，就是这样...等待它不打开？
What's happening? What's happening?
发生了什么事？发生了什么事？
Ah, ok, now, oh my god.
啊，好的，现在，哦，天哪。
Ok, uh, beacon, beacon, no no no it's...
好的，呃，信标，信标，不，不，这是...
Dammit, then which one is it?
该死，那是哪一个？
Ah, here.
啊，在这里。
Oh, yeah.
哦，是的。
So based on the blog, you can get blog sidecars here.
因此，根据博客，您可以在此处获取博客餐饮。
The blogs are not really interesting to users.
这些博客对用户并不有趣。
You don't really have a need to get them unless you are doing archiving of the layer to history
除非您要对历史记录进行归档，否则您实际上并不需要获得它们
or something.
或一些东西。
You don't need to access blogs.
您无需访问博客。
What you might want to see is the transactions in Mempool, which is...
您可能想看到的是Mempool中的交易，那就是...
Come on, it should be...
来吧，应该是...
Sorry, I'm disappointed by this talk now.
抱歉，我现在对这次演讲感到失望。
But this is just it namespace.
但这只是IT名称空间。
So you can get transaction by hash, but you don't want to do that.
因此，您可以通过哈希进行交易，但是您不想这样做。
What you want to do is use the takes pool in here.
您想做的就是在这里使用“ tote池”。
it lets you look into it.
它使您可以研究它。
You see it takes more content, it's
您会看到它需要更多的内容，这是
what you're looking for if you want to see it.
如果您想看它，您正在寻找什么。
Yeah, and of course, the session is recorded.
是的，当然，会议记录。
So this was recorded.
所以记录了这一点。
Now I will shut it down and switch to Jitsi
现在我将其关闭并切换到Jitsi
for more live sessions.
有关更多现场会议。
So if you have more things to ask or whatever,
因此，如果您有更多的询问或其他问题，
we can go to the Jitsi.
我们可以去吉西。
So yeah, I guess that's the show.
是的，我想那是节目。
I think that's it, guys.
我认为就是这样，伙计们。
All right. Thanks so much, Mario, for this.
好的。非常感谢，马里奥。
And yeah, if you want to continue to participate
是的，如果您想继续参加
and get some hands-on assistance from Mario,
并从马里奥（Mario）获得一些动手帮助，
head on into the Jitsi.
前往吉西。
Thanks, everybody.
谢谢，大家。
Yeah, thank you so much for making it
是的，非常感谢您的制作
through the whole two hours with me.
整个两个小时与我在一起。
I appreciate it.
我很感激。
And I hope you learned something.
我希望你学到了一些东西。
I hope it wasn't too basic
我希望这不是太基础
and gave you some useful skills.
并给了您一些有用的技能。
Maybe, yeah.
也许，是的。
or we'll more agency see you guys thanks josh thanks everyone bye
否则我们将更多的代理商见到你们，谢谢乔什，谢谢大家再见